<infobuttons>
    <infobutton description="Type Of Foundation(s)" number="386">
        <item name="Slab-on grade" number="1">Slab-on grade</item>
        <item name="Pier and beam" number="2">Pier and beam</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Type(s) of Roof Covering" number="387">
        <item name="Composition Roofing Material" number="1">Composition Roofing Material</item>
        <item name="Tile Roofing Material" number="2">Tile Roofing Material</item>
        <item name="Wood Roofing Material" number="3">Wood Roofing Material</item>
        <item name="Metal Roofing Material" number="4">Metal Roofing Material</item>
        <item name="Slate Roofing Material" number="5">Slate Roofing Material</item>
        <item name="Low Slope Built-up Roofing Material" number="6">Low Slope Built-up Roofing Material</item>
        <item name="Modified Bitumen Roofing Material" number="7">Modified Bitumen Roofing Material</item>
        <item name="Fiber Cement Roofing Material" number="8">Fiber Cement Roofing Material</item>
        <item name="Asphalt composition shingle" number="9">Asphalt composition shingle</item>
        <item name="Fiberglass composition shingle" number="10">Fiberglass composition shingle</item>
        <item name="Wood shake" number="11">Wood shake</item>
        <item name="Wood shingle" number="12">Wood Shingle</item>
        <item name="Metal" number="13">Metal</item>
        <item name="Clay tile" number="14">Clay Tile</item>
        <item name="Roll roofing" number="15">Roll Roofing</item>
        <item name="Built up roofing" number="16">Built Up Roofing</item>
        <item name="Single ply membrane" number="17">Single Ply Membrane</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Method used to Inspect Roof" number="388">
        <item name="Walked on roof" number="1">Walked On Roof</item>
        <item name="Inspected from ground level" number="2">Inspected from ground level</item>
        <item name="Inspected from drip edge with ladder" number="3">Inspected from drip edge with ladder</item>
        <item name="Due to the steep pitch of the roof structure and design, the roof was observed from ground level with binoculars.  The Inspector felt it would be unsafe to get on and stay on the roof." number="4">Due to the steep pitch of the roof structure and design, the roof was observed from ground level with binoculars.  The Inspector felt it would be unsafe to get on and stay on the roof.</item>
        <item name="Due to the steep pitch of the roof structure design, the roof was observed from the roof structure drip edge.  The Inspector felt it would be unsafe to get on and stay on the roof." number="5">Due to the steep pitch of the roof structure design, the roof was observed from the roof structure drip edge.  The Inspector felt it would be unsafe to get on and stay on the roof.</item>
        <item name="The roof was observed from ground level with binoculars. The two-story home roof level does not have readable safe access." number="6">The roof was observed from ground level with binoculars. The two-story home roof level does not have readable safe access.</item>
        <item name="Walked on roof" number="7">Walked On Roof</item>
        <item name="Viewed from ladder at eave" number="8">Viewed From Ladder At Eave</item>
        <item name="Viewed with binoculars" number="9">Viewed With Binoculars</item>
        <item name="Viewed from window" number="10">Viewed From Window</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Method used to Inspect Attic" number="389">
        <item name="Interior of Attic" number="1">Interior of Attic</item>
        <item name="Attic hatch with ladder, attic was not entered due to low clearances." number="2">Attic hatch with ladder, attic was not entered due to low clearances.</item>
        <item name="Attic ladder, attic was not entered due to low clearances." number="3">Attic ladder, attic was not entered due to low clearances.</item>
        <item name="Attic ladder, attic was not entered due to heavy storage." number="4">Attic ladder, attic was not entered due to heavy storage.</item>
        <item name="Entered attic and performed a visual inspection" number="5">Entered attic and performed a visual inspection</item>
        <item name="Viewed attic from access hatch" number="6">Viewed attic from access hatch</item>
        <item name="None - no access hatch found" number="7">None - no access hatch found</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Insulation Depth" number="390">
        <item name="0 to 3&quot;" number="1">0 to 3"</item>
        <item name="4&quot; to 6&quot;" number="2">4" to 6"</item>
        <item name="7&quot; to 9&quot;" number="3">7" to 9"</item>
        <item name="10&quot; to 13&quot;" number="4">10" to 13"</item>
        <item name="13+&quot;" number="5">13+"</item>
        <item name="No Insulation in place" number="6">No Insulation in place</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Type Of Wiring" number="391">
        <item name="Copper" number="1">Copper</item>
        <item name="Aluminum" number="2">Aluminum</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Type(s) of Heating Systems" number="392">
        <item name="Central Forced Air Furnace" number="1">Central Forced Air Furnace</item>
        <item name="Heat Pump" number="2">The installation of a heat pump system may be a logical long term improvement, depending on the such things as the anticipated term of ownership and current heating and air conditioning costs.</item>
        <item name="Baseboard" number="3">Baseboard</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Engery Source" number="393">
        <item name="Gas" number="1">Gas</item>
        <item name="Electricity" number="2">Electricity</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Type(s) of Cooling Systems" number="394">
        <item name="Central Forced Air System" number="1">Central Forced Air System</item>
        <item name="Window Unit" number="2">Window Unit</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Location of Water Meter" number="395">
        <item name="Within 5-feet of Front Curb" number="1">Within 5-feet of Front Curb</item>
        <item name="Within 5-feet of Back Alley" number="2">Within 5-feet of Back Alley</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Location of Main Water Supply Valve" number="396">
        <item name="I was unable to locate a main water supply valve." number="1">I was unable to locate a main water supply valve.</item>
        <item name="Within 3-feet of the north exterior wall." number="2">Within 3-feet of the north exterior wall.</item>
        <item name="Within 3-feet of the east exterior wall." number="3">Within 3-feet of the east exterior wall.</item>
        <item name="Within 3-feet of the south exterior wall." number="4">Within 3-feet of the south exterior wall.</item>
        <item name="Within 3-feet of the west exterior wall." number="5">Within 3-feet of the west exterior wall.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Water Heater Capacity" number="397">
        <item name="50 Gallons" number="1">50 Gallons</item>
        <item name="55 Gallons" number="2">55 Gallons</item>
        <item name="52 Gallons" number="3">52 Gallons</item>
        <item name="40 Gallons" number="4">40 Gallons</item>
        <item name="35 Gallons" number="5">35 Gallons</item>
        <item name="30 Gallons" number="6">30 Gallons</item>
        <item name="65 Gallons" number="7">65 Gallons</item>
        <item name="75 Gallons" number="8">75 Gallons</item>
        <item name="80 Gallons" number="9">80 Gallons</item>
        <item name="100 Gallons" number="10">100 Gallons</item>
        <item name="Could Not Determine" number="11">Could Not Determine</item>
        <item name="Inline Tankless Water Heater" number="12">Inline Tankless Water Heater</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Swimming Pool Construction Type" number="398">
        <item name="In Ground - Concrete Type" number="1">In Ground - Concrete Type</item>
        <item name="In Ground - Fiberglass Type" number="2">In Ground - Fiberglass Type</item>
        <item name="In Ground - Vinyl Lined Type" number="3">In Ground - Vinyl Lined Type</item>
        <item name="Above Ground - Vinyl Lined Type" number="4">Above Ground - Vinyl Lined Type</item>
        <item name="Above Ground - Fiberglass Type" number="5">Above Ground - Fiberglass Type</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Type of Septic System" number="399">
        <item name="Traditional Type Septic System" number="1">Traditional Type Septic System</item>
        <item name="Aerobic Type Septic System" number="2">Aerobic Type Septic System</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="Type of Well Pump" number="400"/>
    <infobutton description="Type of Well Storage Equipment" number="401"/>
    <infobutton description="Location of Drain Field:" number="402"/>
    <infobutton description="Foundation Description" number="403">
        <item name="performing as intended.  No significant problems were observed" number="1">performing as intended.  No significant problems were observed</item>
        <item name="not performing as intended.  See additional comments below." number="2">not performing as intended.  See additional comments below.</item>
        <item name="in need of major repair.  See additional comments below" number="3">in need of major repair.  See additional comments below</item>
        <item name="in need of complete replacement.  See additional comments below" number="4">in need of complete replacement.  See additional comments below</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="FOUNDATION COMMENTS" number="404">
        <item name="Cracks Minor/Settling" number="1">Common minor cracks were observed in the foundation walls of the house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses. New Item Need to be redefined</item>
        <item name="Cracks Minor/Shrinkage" number="2">Minor vertical cracking was observed in the foundation.  This type of cracking is usually the result of shrinkage of the concrete as it cures.  Shrinkage cracks are very common and should not be cause for alarm.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Moderate/Settling" number="3">Slightly greater than typical foundation cracking was observed.  The amount of movement does not suggest a serious structural problem.  This area should, of course, be monitored.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Major/Settling" number="4">Substantial foundation cracking was observed.  This implies that structural movement of the building has occurred.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.  A structural engineer should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Spalling (Exterior)" number="5">Surface deterioration (known as spalling) was observed on the exterior of the exposed foundation walls.  This condition is common in many homes and does not usually represent a structural concern.  In an effort to prevent long term deterioration, it would be wise to consider parging deteriorated areas.  Lot drainage improvements, as outlined in the "Exterior" section of this report are also recommended.</item>
        <item name="Mortar Deterioration (Exterior)" number="6">Foundation wall mortar joints show evidence of deterioration.  It would be wise to consider repointing deteriorated areas in order to improve durability.</item>
        <item name="Backfill Height Excessive" number="7">The height of the backfill (soil adjacent to the foundation) appears to exceed the acceptable limit.  This could result in excessive force on the foundation.  A structural engineer or qualified contractor should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Exterior Wall Cracks" number="8">Cracks were observed on the exterior walls of the house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Interior Wall Cracks" number="9">Cracks were observed on the interior walls of the house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Door Frames" number="10">Door frames were found to be out-of-square within house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Floor Slope" number="11">Sloping floors were observed within house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Cable Ends Visible" number="12">Post tension cable ends were observed on the exterior of the foundation.  This should be repaired to prevent corrosion.</item>
        <item name="Wood Debris /Trash" number="13">All wood debris and/or trash should be removed from the crawl space.</item>
        <item name="Wood/Soil Contact" number="14">Crawl space wood/soil contact should be eliminated.  This condition is conducive to rot and wood boring insect activity.</item>
        <item name="Seal Openings" number="15">All potential vermin entry points to the crawl space should be sealed.</item>
        <item name="Vermin Activity" number="16">There is evidence of vermin activity in the crawl space.  A pest control specialist should be consulted in this regard.</item>
        <item name="Secure Ducting" number="17">Loose ductwork in the crawl space should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Past/Seasonal Water" number="18">There is evidence of past water in the crawl space.  This condition may vary seasonally and/or with precipitation intensity.  Lot drainage improvements should be addressed as a first step to controlling water in the crawl space.  This condition should then be monitored to determine if drainage tiles are necessary.</item>
        <item name="Wall Vent Obstructed" number="19">Obstructed crawl space wall vents should be cleared or opened.</item>
        <item name="Missing/Damaged Screens" number="20">Missing or damaged crawl space vent screens should be repaired as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Ventilation Needed" number="21">Ventilation of the crawl space is insufficient.  One (1) square foot of free vent area should be provided for every five hundred (500) square feet of crawl space.  Proper ventilation will help to control humidity and reduce the potential for rot.  Crawl spaces can be vented to the building interior or exterior, depending on the configuration of the crawl space.</item>
        <item name="Mildew Due To Poor Ventilation" number="22">Evidence of mildew was observed in the crawl space.  This is suspected to be related to improper ventilation.  One (1) square foot of free vent area should be provided for every five hundred (500) square feet of crawl space.  Proper ventilation will help to control humidity and reduce the potential for rot.  Crawl spaces can be vented to the building interior or exterior, depending on the configuration of the crawl space.</item>
        <item name="Adjust Moisture Barrier" number="23">The crawl space moisture barrier should be spread out to cover all exposed soil.</item>
        <item name="Repair Moisture Barrier" number="24">The crawl space moisture barrier should be repaired where damaged or incomplete.</item>
        <item name="Moisture Barrier Needed" number="25">A moisture barrier should be installed on the crawl space floor.</item>
        <item name="Foam Board Exposed" number="26">The exposed foam board insulation in the crawl space represents a fire hazard.  Although this is a common occurrence, it is recommended that this insulation be removed or covered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-A" number="27">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to inspect flatwork or detention/ retention pond (expect as related to slope and drainage); determine area hydrology or the presence or underground water; or determine the efficiency or operation of underground or surface drainage systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="GRADING / DRAINAGE COMMENTS" number="405">
        <item name="Low Lot Relative To Neighbor" number="1">The lot is lower than adjacent lots.  Grading improvements should be undertaken where possible.  The general topography of the area is such that it will be difficult to control storm water entirely.  During heavy rains or snow melts, the accumulation of storm water on the lot may be unavoidable.  This could also influence moisture in the basement.  Refer to the Interior section of the report for comments regarding evidence of basement moisture.</item>
        <item name="Grading Improvement Needed" number="2">The grading should be improved to promote the flow of storm water away from the house.  This can usually be accomplished by the addition of top soil.  The ground should slope away from the house at a rate of one inch per foot for at least the first ten feet.  Ideally, at least eight (8) inches of clearance should be maintained between soil level and the top of the foundation walls.</item>
        <item name="Swale Improvement Bet. Houses" number="3">A drainage swale (if effect, a wide and shallow ditch) should be created.  Drainage swales are intended to divert storm water away from the house and ultimately off the lot.</item>
        <item name="Driveway Slopes Towards House" number="4">The driveway appears to slope towards the house.  This condition can promote moisture seepage.  Unfortunately, it is difficult to improve this situation without resurfacing the driveway adjacent to the foundation.</item>
        <item name="Seal Driveway At House" number="5">The driveway should be sealed where it meets the house.</item>
        <item name="Walkway Slopes Towards House" number="6">The walkway appears to slope towards the house.  This condition can promote moisture seepage.  It is difficult to improve this situation without re-grading the walkway adjacent to the foundation.</item>
        <item name="Ravine Erosion Problem?" number="7">An evaluation of soil stability is beyond the scope of this inspection.  As with many ravine lots, there is potential for erosion.  If erosion problems are suspected, a soils engineer should be consulted to evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-B" number="8">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to inspect flatwork or detention/ retention pond (expect as related to slope and drainage); determine area hydrology or the presence or underground water; or determine the efficiency or operation of underground or surface drainage systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="ROOF COVERING COMMENTS" number="406">
        <item name="Minor Repairs Only" number="1">Minor repairs to the roofing are recommended.  Damaged or missing roofing material should be repaired.  All roof penetrations should be examined and sealed as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Replacement Needed" number="2">The roofing was found to be in poor condition and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Nearing End Of Life Cycle" number="3">The roofing is nearing the end of its life cycle.  Replacement will become necessary in the near future.</item>
        <item name="Near End Of Life Cycle - Minor" number="4">The roofing is nearing the end of its life cycle.  Minor repairs are recommended in the short term to maintain the weather tightness of the roof.  Damaged or missing roofing material should be repaired.  All roof penetrations should be examined and sealed as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition" number="5">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.</item>
        <item name="Fair Cond. - Amateur Install" number="6">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  The installation of this roofing appears to have been performed in an amateur fashion.  While this condition does not pose a serious short term concern, it may effect the reliability and/or longevity of the roof.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition - Uneven Wear" number="7">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  This roofing is wearing at uneven rates.  The sides of the roof that are most exposed to the sun’s light are wearing more quickly than the more shaded areas.  Repair or replacement of deteriorated roofing may be needed in some areas, prior to the entire roof covering requiring replacement.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition - Premature Flaws" number="8">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  The roofing shows evidence of flaws that are premature for roofing of this age.  This may be a manufacturing defect.  This condition may influence the life expectancy of the roofing.  The manufacturer of installer could be consulted for further evaluation.</item>
        <item name="Good Cond. - Amateur Install" number="9">The roofing is considered to be in good condition.  The installation of this roofing appears to have been performed in an amateur fashion.  While this does not pose a serious short term concern, it may have a longer term affect on the reliability and/or longevity of the roof.</item>
        <item name="Good Condition - Uneven Wear" number="10">The roofing is considered to be in good condition.  This roofing is wearing at uneven rates.  The sides of the roof that are most exposed to the sun’s light are wearing more quickly than the more shaded areas.  Repair or replacement of deteriorated roofing may be needed in some areas, prior to the entire roof covering requiring replacement.</item>
        <item name="Inappropriate Mat. - Low Slope" number="11">The roofing is not intended for this low slope application.  While this condition does not pose a serious short term concern, it may affect the reliability and longevity of this section of roof.</item>
        <item name="Older Roofs - Maintenance Notes" number="12">Older roofs are, by their nature, a high maintenance roof.  Annual inspection and repair should be anticipated.  In addition, the older flashings should be monitored.  In some cases, a deteriorated flashing can result in expensive repairs, because sections of the roofing have to be removed.  As a rule of thumb, replacement of the entire roof covering may be logical if more than ten percent of the roof requires repair.</item>
        <item name="Vulnerable Areas" number="13">The design of the roofing system is such that several vulnerable areas exist.  There is a higher potential for unanticipated repairs.  Annual inspections and ongoing maintenance will be critical to the performance of the roofing system.</item>
        <item name="Prior Repairs Evident" number="14">Prior repairs to the roofing are evident.  This would suggest that problems have been experienced in the past.  This area should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Remove Debris" number="15">Debris should be removed from the roofing.</item>
        <item name="Exposed Felt/Sheathing" number="16">Exposed sheathing is visible where the roofing is damaged.  Damaged or missing roofing material should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Strip When Re-Roofing" number="17">It is recommended that roofing materials be removed prior to re-roofing.</item>
        <item name="Replacement Needed" number="18">The roofing was found to be in poor condition and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Nearing End Of Life Cycle" number="19">The roofing is nearing the end of its life cycle.  Replacement will become necessary in the near future.</item>
        <item name="Near End Of Life - Flaws" number="20">The roofing is nearing the end of its life cycle.  The membrane exhibits flaws (such as blistering, cracking, etc.) that are symptomatic of an older flat roof.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition" number="21">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.</item>
        <item name="Fair Cond. - Material/Install" number="22">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  The installation of this roofing appears to have been performed in an amateur fashion.  This roofing material is not ideally suited to a flat roof application.  While this condition does not pose a serious short term concern, it may affect the reliability and/or longevity of the roof.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition - Lack Of Gravel" number="23">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  The lack of gravel on the membrane has led to a shortened life expectancy.  Applying gravel over the membrane may help to prolong the life of this roof.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition - Water Ponding" number="24">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  Water appears to pond on the membrane.  This usually leads to a shortened life expectancy and increases the potential for damage if leakage occurs.  Improvement is not usually practical until re-roofing is performed.  At that time, the roof should be appropriately sloped, or drains should be provided as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Amateur Install - Good Cond." number="25">The roofing is considered to be in reasonably good condition.  The installation of this roofing appears to have been performed in an amateur fashion.  This roofing material is not ideally suited to a flat roof application.  While this condition does not pose a serious short term concern, it may affect the reliability and/or longevity of the roof.</item>
        <item name="Drains Congested" number="26">The congested roof drains should be cleared and maintained free of debris.</item>
        <item name="UV Protect. Needed - Single Ply" number="27">Ideally, some form of ultraviolet protection would be provided for the membrane.  This protection typically comes in the form of paint, foil or gravel.</item>
        <item name="Incompatible Materials" number="28">The membrane may not be compatible to the adjoining asphalt roofing.  A qualified licensed roofer should be consulted.</item>
        <item name="Voids In Gravel" number="29">Voids in the gravel were observed on the roofing.  This usually leads to a shortened life expectancy and increases the potential for ultraviolet damage to the roofing.  Missing gravel should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Seam Failure" number="30">The roofing shows evidence of seam failure (the seams of the membrane coming apart).  Repairs are recommended.</item>
        <item name="Typical Maintenance Needed" number="31">The roofing requires maintenance.  Moss should be cleared from the roof, voids in the gravel should be improved, and any blisters should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Prior Repairs Evident" number="32">Prior repairs to the roofing are evident.  This would suggest that problems have been experienced in the past.  This area should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Strip When Re-Roofing" number="33">It is recommended that roofing materials be removed prior to re-roofing.</item>
        <item name="Old - Replacement Needed" number="34">The flashing is old and should be replaced to avoid leaks.</item>
        <item name="Leak - Replacement Needed" number="35">The flashing leaks and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Leak - Patching Needed" number="36">The flashing leaks and should be patched. If this is unsuccessful, replacement will be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Vulnerable - Prior Leak" number="37">The flashing is vulnerable, has leaked in the past, and should be watched carefully for leaks.</item>
        <item name="Holes - Temporary Patching" number="38">Holes were observed in the flashing. If patching is unsuccessful, replacement will be necessary to stop leaks.</item>
        <item name="Holes - Replacement Needed" number="39">Holes were observed in the flashing. It should be replaced to stop leaks.</item>
        <item name="Rust" number="40">The flashing is rusting. It should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Loose" number="41">The flashing is loose and should be re-secured to avoid leaks.</item>
        <item name="Incomplete Installation" number="42">The installation of the flashing is incomplete and should be repaired to avoid leaks.</item>
        <item name="Nail Heads Exposed" number="43">Nail heads are exposed at the flashing. They should be sealed to reduce risk of leaks.</item>
        <item name="Lack Of Clearance - Siding/Roof" number="44">The clearance of the siding at the flashing is insufficient. This condition leaves the siding vulnerable to rot. This detail is usually repaired when siding needs repair or replacement or when re-roofing work is performed.</item>
        <item name="Skylight - Install Low Quality" number="45">The installation of the skylight is low quality and will be extremely vulnerable to leakage.  Repair is recommended.</item>
        <item name="Skylight Leakage" number="46">The flashing shows evidence of leaks. In some cases, patching the flashing will prevent leaks. If this approach is unsuccessful, re-installing the skylight may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Cracked/Broken" number="47">The skylight is cracked. It should be repaired for safety and to avoid leaks.</item>
        <item name="Cleaning Needed" number="48">The gutters require cleaning to avoid spilling roof runoff around the building – a potential source of water entry or water damage.</item>
        <item name="Leaks Minor" number="49">Minor leaks in the gutters should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Slope Insufficient" number="50">The gutters do not appear to have sufficient slope to drain properly. If they do not perform as intended, the slope should be adjusted to avoid spilling roof runoff around the building – a potential source of water entry or water damage.</item>
        <item name="Gutters Damaged" number="51">Damaged gutters should be repaired or replaced as necessary to avoid spilling roof runoff around the building – a potential source of water entry or water damage.</item>
        <item name="Old Steel - Eventual Replace" number="52">The old galvanized gutters and downspouts are rusting noticeably. Replacement should be anticipated over the next few years. In the interim, leaks that develop should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Old Steel - Replacement" number="53">The old galvanized gutters and downspouts should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Downspouts Insufficient Number" number="54">There does not appear to be a sufficient number of downspouts. If practical, additional downspouts should be installed to avoid spilling roof runoff around the building – a potential source of water entry or water damage.</item>
        <item name="Downspout Discharge Near House" number="55">The downspout(s) should discharge water at least five (5) feet from the house. Storm water should be encouraged to flow away from the building at the point of discharge.</item>
        <item name="Downspouts Clogged Below Grade?" number="56">The downspouts that discharge below grade level should be monitored. If they are ever suspected to be clogged or disconnected below grade, they should be redirected to discharge at least five (5) feet from the building. Foundation leakage adjacent to a downspout is an indication of a problem below grade.</item>
        <item name="Downspout Discharge Onto Roof" number="57">Downspout(s) that discharge onto the roof should be extended to discharge directly into the gutters below. This condition, if left unattended, can result in premature deterioration of the roofing under the end of the downspout.</item>
        <item name="Downspout Loose/Damaged" number="58">Loose or damaged downspouts should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-C" number="59">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to determine the remaining life expectancy of the roof covering; inspect the roof from the roof level if, in the inspector’s reasonable judgment, the inspector cannot safely reach or stay on the roof, or significant damage to the roof covering materials may result from walking on the roof; determine the number of layers of roof covering material; identify latent hail damage; or provide an exhaustive list of locations of water penetrations or previous repairs.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="ROOF STRUCTURE / ATTIC COMMENTS" number="407">
        <item name="Ridge Sag" number="1">The ridge of the roof appears to have sagged.  This condition is common in many older homes. Strengthening the roof structure would resist further movement.</item>
        <item name="Rafter Sag" number="2">The rafters of the roof structure show evidence of sagging.  Strengthening the roof structure would resist further movement.</item>
        <item name="Collar Ties Insufficient" number="3">Ideally, collar ties (horizontal members running between each rafter, near their mid-span) should be provided for all rafters.  Collar ties help to resist rafter sag.  Installation is usually very simple.</item>
        <item name="Sheathing Unevenness (Truss)" number="4">Some unevenness in the roof sheathing was observed.  This condition is common where prefabricated roof trusses are used, and spaced two feet apart.  The sheathing sags between the trusses.</item>
        <item name="Truss Uplift" number="5">As evidenced by cracking at the intersection of the interior wall and ceiling, the roof structure appears to suffer from "truss uplift".  This condition is not uncommon in homes employing prefabricated trusses in colder climates.  Truss uplift itself does not represent a serious structural concern.  Cosmetic improvements on the interior of the home, such as the installation of a cove moulding secured to the ceiling, may be desirable to disguise interior cracks.</item>
        <item name="Truss Cut/Altered" number="6">The trusses of the roof structure appear to have been altered.  Cutting or altering the chords of a truss can sacrifice the integrity of the truss.  Special engineering considerations are usually required when trusses are altered.  This area should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="FBM Plywood" number="7">It is suspected that FBM (Fire Retardant Treated) Plywood has been used as roof sheathing.  This type of sheathing is prone to de-lamination and weakening.  This roof sheathing should be carefully monitored.  Sections that begin to fail should be replaced.  During any re-roofing, sheathing improvements would be logical.</item>
        <item name="Sheathing Condensation" number="8">Evidence of condensation (in the form of mildew) was observed on the underside of the roof sheathing.  This condition can weaken the sheathing and ultimately necessitate replacement.  Improved roof and attic ventilation (see Insulation and Ventilation) typically control condensation.  During any planned re-roofing, the sheathing should be investigated to determine if replacement is needed.</item>
        <item name="Sheathing Delaminated" number="9">The roof sheathing is de-laminating (deterioration caused by moisture).  In most cases, damaged roof sheathing must be replaced prior to re-roofing.  Improved roof and attic ventilation (see Insulation and Ventilation) typically control moisture levels within the roof structure.  This condition should be further investigated when re-roofing.</item>
        <item name="Insulation Stains Noted" number="10">Stains on the insulation were observed as evidence of prior roof leakage.</item>
        <item name="Major Leaks Noted" number="11">Substantial evidence of roof leakage was observed.  This condition should be investigated further and repairs made, as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Holes/Light Visible" number="12">While investigating the roof structure, outside light was visible.  This condition suggests that openings exist in the roofing materials.  Repairs should be made, as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Prior Repairs Noted" number="13">Prior repairs to the roof structure are evident.  It may be wise to consult the current owner regarding their knowledge of the roof structure and/or any repairs that became necessary.</item>
        <item name="Improve Insulation" number="14">Insulation improvements may be cost effective, depending on the anticipated term of ownership.</item>
        <item name="Even Out Insulation" number="15">Insulation should be evened out.</item>
        <item name="Compressed Insulation" number="16">Compressed insulation should be rearranged.</item>
        <item name="Skylight Well Insulation Needed" number="17">The skylight well should be better insulated.</item>
        <item name="Improve Ventilation" number="18">The level of ventilation should be improved.  It is generally recommended that one (1) square foot of free vent area be provided for every one hundred and fifty (150) square feet of ceiling area.  Proper ventilation will help to keep the house cooler during warm weather and extend the life of roofing materials.  In colder climates, it will help reduce the potential for ice dams on the roof and condensation within the attic.</item>
        <item name="Marginal Ventilation" number="19">The level of ventilation is considered marginal.  It is generally recommended that one (1) square foot of free vent area be provided for every one hundred and fifty (150) square feet of ceiling area.  Proper ventilation will help to keep the house cooler during warm weather and extend the life of roofing materials.  In colder climates, it will help reduce the potential for ice dams on the roof and condensation within the attic.</item>
        <item name="Soffit Vents Congested?" number="20">The passage of air between the soffit vents and the roof cavity appears to be obstructed.  "Baffles" should be provided to hold back insulation and allow for free movement of air within the roof space.  This area should be further investigated and improved where necessary.</item>
        <item name="Screens On Vents Needed" number="21">Roof vents should be screened to prevent insect and vermin entry.</item>
        <item name="Sloped Ceil. Questionable Vent." number="22">The ventilation of the sloped ceiling is questionable.  Proper ventilation of cathedral roofs is rarely achieved.  As a result, these areas tend to be prone to difficulty, particularly in colder climates.  Ice damming on the roof and condensation within the roof space are common problems.  These areas should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Condensation/Mildew" number="23">Evidence of condensation and mildew was observed.  This condition is usually the result of insufficient ventilation.  Ventilation should be improved and this area should be monitored.  If ignored, this situation could worsen and cause substantial rot.</item>
        <item name="Power Ventilator Inoperative" number="24">The power ventilator appears to be inoperative.  The unit should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Access Hatch Needs Insulation" number="25">Ideally, the attic access hatch should be better insulated.</item>
        <item name="Ducts In Attic Need Insulation" number="26">The ductwork should be better insulated.  This should reduce energy costs.</item>
        <item name="Vent Exhaust Fan To Outside" number="27">Exhaust vent pipes should be insulated and vented to the building exterior.</item>
        <item name="Exhaust Vent Needs Insulation" number="28">Insulation should be provided on exhaust vent pipes.</item>
        <item name="Check Out Recessed Lights" number="29">Recessed lights can pose a fire hazard if not specifically designed for installation in an insulated ceiling.  It is recommended that a licensed electrician be contacted to further evaluate these light fixtures.</item>
        <item name="Vermin Activity Noted" number="30">There is evidence of vermin activity.  A pest control specialist should be consulted in this regard.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-D" number="31">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to enter attics or unfinished spaces where openings are less than 22 inches by 30 inches or headroom is less than 30 inches; operate powered ventilators; or provide an exhaustive list of locations or water penetrations.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="WALLS (INTERIOR / EXTERIOR) COMMENTS" number="408">
        <item name="Water Staining" number="1">Water staining was noted.  The cause for the staining should be determined and repairs undertaken, if necessary, to prevent structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Damage" number="2">ined</item>
        <item name="Patching" number="3">Evidence of patching was detected.</item>
        <item name="Damage Noted" number="4">Damage to the interior finish was observed and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Minor Cracks" number="5">Minor cracks were noted.  This condition is mainly cosmetic in nature and should be patched.</item>
        <item name="Larger Cracks" number="6">Larger than typical cracks were noted. This condition could indicate greater than normal movement within the structure and potential structural problems.  Further investigation may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Drywall Flaws" number="7">Typical drywall flaws were observed. This condition is mainly cosmetic in nature and should be patched.</item>
        <item name="Loose/Weakened" number="8">Loose or weakened finishes were detected.  This should be repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Bulging Plaster" number="9">The plaster shows evidence of bulging.  Repairs may be desirable.</item>
        <item name="Weakness In Plaster" number="10">The plaster finishes show evidence of weakening, as is common in many older homes.  This should be repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Amateur Installation" number="11">The installation of interior finishes is considered to be amateur quality.</item>
        <item name="Poor Workmanship" number="12">Evidence of substandard workmanship was observed.</item>
        <item name="Installation Incomplete" number="13">The installation of interior finishes is incomplete.</item>
        <item name="Mildew" number="14">Signs of mildew were observed. The cause should be investigated and/or repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Staining" number="15">Water staining was noted.  The cause for the staining should be determined and repairs undertaken, if necessary, to prevent structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Damage" number="16">ined</item>
        <item name="Cracks Typical" number="17">Typical minor cracking was observed on the exterior walls of the house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Moderate" number="18">Slightly larger than typical exterior wall cracking was observed.  The amount of movement does not suggest a serious structural problem.  This area should, of course, be monitored.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Major" number="19">Pronounced exterior wall cracks were observed.  This implies that structural movement of the building has occurred.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.  A structural engineer should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Weep Holes Blocked" number="20">Blocked weep holes (openings in the mortar joints, typically found at foundation level) in the brick veneer wall structure should be cleared.</item>
        <item name="Corbelling Excessive" number="21">The overhang of the brick at the foundation wall, also known as corbelling, is excessive.  This could lead to some instability of the brickwork.  If movement occurs, re-supporting the brick would be advisable.</item>
        <item name="Lintel Movement/Cracks" number="22">Exterior wall cracks above a lintel (in effect, a beam supporting the brickwork above an opening in the wall) suggests that the lintel may be marginally adequate.  This condition is not uncommon.</item>
        <item name="Bowing" number="23">Bowing of the exterior wall structure was observed.  This implies that structural movement of the building has occurred.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.  A structural engineer should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Leaning" number="24">The exterior wall structure is leaning.  This implies that structural movement of the building has occurred.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.  A structural engineer should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-E" number="25">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to report cosmetic damage or the condition of floor, wall, or ceiling coverings; paints, stains, or other surface coatings; cabinets; or countertops, or provide an exhaustive list of locations of water penetrations.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="CEILING / FLOOR COMMENTS" number="409">
        <item name="Water Staining" number="1">Water staining was noted.  The cause for the staining should be determined and repairs undertaken, if necessary, to prevent structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Damage" number="2">ined</item>
        <item name="Patching" number="3">Evidence of patching was detected.</item>
        <item name="Damage Noted" number="4">Damage to the interior finish was observed and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Minor Cracks" number="5">Minor cracks were noted.  This condition is mainly cosmetic in nature and should be patched.</item>
        <item name="Larger Cracks" number="6">Larger than typical cracks were noted. This condition could indicate greater than normal movement within the structure and potential structural problems.  Further investigation may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Drywall Flaws" number="7">Typical drywall flaws were observed. This condition is mainly cosmetic in nature and should be patched.</item>
        <item name="Loose/Weakened" number="8">Loose or weakened finishes were detected.  This should be repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Bulging Plaster" number="9">The plaster shows evidence of bulging.  Repairs may be desirable.</item>
        <item name="Weakness In Plaster" number="10">The plaster finishes show evidence of weakening, as is common in many older homes.  This should be repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Amateur Installation" number="11">The installation of interior finishes is considered to be amateur quality.</item>
        <item name="Poor Workmanship" number="12">Evidence of substandard workmanship was observed.</item>
        <item name="Installation Incomplete" number="13">The installation of interior finishes is incomplete.</item>
        <item name="Mildew" number="14">Signs of mildew were observed. The cause should be investigated and/or repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Floors Sloping" number="15">Floor slopes are apparent. This condition could indicate greater than normal movement within the structure and potential structural problems.  Further investigation may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Floors Sagging" number="16">Sagging floors are apparent. This condition could indicate greater than normal movement within the structure and potential structural problems.  Further investigation may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Tile Cracked" number="17">The tile floor is cracked and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Tile Cracked/Loose" number="18">The tile floor is loose and/or cracked.  This should be repaired before it becomes a trip hazard.</item>
        <item name="Tile Installation Marginal" number="19">The installation of the tile floor is less than ideal.  It is very common for tile floors to be installed without the benefit of sufficient underlayment or floor stiffening.  This can influence the long term performance of the floor.</item>
        <item name="Vinyl Seams Poor" number="20">Seams in the vinyl flooring are not in ideal condition.  Improvement is discretionary.</item>
        <item name="Vinyl Damage" number="21">The vinyl flooring is damaged and may be in need of repair or replacement.</item>
        <item name="Vinyl Poor Installation" number="22">The installation of the vinyl flooring is not ideal and may be in need of repair or replacement.</item>
        <item name="Carpet Stains" number="23">Stains were noted on the carpet.</item>
        <item name="Carpet Odor" number="24">The carpet appears to emit an odor.  Cleaning and deodorizing may be desirable.</item>
        <item name="Trim Loose" number="25">The floor trim is loose and should be re-secured.</item>
        <item name="Trim Incomplete" number="26">The installation of the floor trim is incomplete.</item>
        <item name="Stair Handrail Loose" number="27">Loose stairway handrails should be better secured.</item>
        <item name="Stair Handrail Needed" number="28">For improved safety, it is recommended that a railings be provided for the stairway.</item>
        <item name="Stair Railing Loose" number="29">The railing for the stairway is loose and should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Stair Railing Needed" number="30">For improved safety, it is recommended that a railing be provided for the stairway.</item>
        <item name="Railing Loose" number="31">The railing is loose and should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Railing Needed" number="32">For improved safety, it is recommended that a railing be provided.</item>
        <item name="Railing Openings" number="33">The openings in the railing are large enough to allow an object larger than four inches to fall through. It is recommended that this condition be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Railing Height" number="34">The height of the railing may not be sufficient to prevent a person from toppling over the railing. It is recommended that this condition be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-F" number="35">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to report cosmetic damage or the condition of floor, wall, or ceiling coverings; paints, stains, or other surface coatings; cabinets; or countertops, or provide an exhaustive list of locations of water penetrations.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="DOORS (INTERIOR/EXTERIOR) COMMENTS" number="410">
        <item name="General Trimming/Adjustment" number="1">Doors should be trimmed or adjusted as necessary to work properly.</item>
        <item name="Door Hardware Damaged" number="2">Damaged or non-functional door hardware should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Doors" number="3">Damaged or non-functional doors should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Door Water Damage" number="4">Water damage was observed adjacent to the door.  The cause should be determined and repaired to ensure proper operation of the door.</item>
        <item name="Door Glass Non-Tempered" number="5">Safety glass etchings were not observed on the glass within the door.  Safety glass is required for glass doors and is generally identified by an etching in the corner of the glass pane.</item>
        <item name="General Trimming/Adjustment" number="6">Doors should be trimmed or adjusted as necessary to work properly.</item>
        <item name="Door Hardware Damaged" number="7">Damaged or non-functional door hardware should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Doors" number="8">Damaged or non-functional doors should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Door Water Damage" number="9">Water damage was observed adjacent to the door.  The cause should be determined and repaired to ensure proper operation of the door.</item>
        <item name="Door Screen Damaged" number="10">The screen for the exterior door is damaged and should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Sticking" number="11">The sliding glass door could be improved to operate freely.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Rollers" number="12">The rollers of the sliding glass door could be improved to operate freely.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Older" number="13">The sliding glass door is older.  While replacement does not represent a high priority, it may be a logical long term goal.  The function and efficiency of a new door would be a substantial improvement.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Screen Damaged" number="14">The screen for the sliding glass door is missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Screen Missing" number="15">The screen for the sliding glass door is missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Hardware Damaged" number="16">The hardware for the sliding glass door is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Lost Seal" number="17">The glass of the sliding glass door has lost its seal.  This has resulted in condensation developing between the panes of glass and can cause the glass to loose it’s insulating properties.  The glass should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Leak At Threshold" number="18">Evidence of leakage was observed at the threshold of the sliding glass door.  Improved caulking would be the first step to improving this condition.</item>
        <item name="Door Glass Non-Tempered" number="19">Safety glass etchings were not observed on the glass within the door.  Safety glass is required for glass doors and is generally identified by an etching in the corner of the glass pane.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door Damage" number="20">The overhead garage door is damaged and needs repair.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door Localized Rot" number="21">The overhead garage door shows evidence of localized rot and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door Extensive Rot" number="22">The overhead garage door is substantially rotted. It should be repaired or replaced as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door Adjustment" number="23">The overhead garage door requires adjustment for easy and safe operation.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door No Safety Springs" number="24">No safety springs/cables were noted on the garage door. The installation of the springs/cables would improve safety during operation.</item>
        <item name="Garage Man Door Closer" number="25">The door between the garage and the interior of the house should be equipped with an auto-closer device to prevent automobile fumes from entering the house.</item>
        <item name="Garage Man Door Rating" number="26">The door between the garage and the interior of the house should be rated to resist fire as per local codes.</item>
        <item name="Garage Man Door Seal" number="27">The door between the garage and the interior of the house should be well sealed to prevent automobile fumes from entering the house.</item>
        <item name="Garage Man Door Adjustment" number="28">The door between the garage and the interior of the house should be adjusted to operate freely, yet fit tightly.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-G" number="29">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to report cosmetic damage or the condition of floor, wall, or ceiling coverings; paints, stains, or other surface coatings; cabinets; or countertops, or provide an exhaustive list of locations of water penetrations.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="WINDOWS COMMENTS" number="411">
        <item name="Old Windows - Mild Disrepair" number="1">The windows are in mild disrepair.  This is a common condition that does not necessitate immediate major repair.  Trimming and adjustment, hardware improvements and glazing repairs would be logical long term improvements.  In practice, improvements are usually made on an as needed basis only.  The most important factor is that the window exteriors are well maintained to avoid rot or water infiltration.</item>
        <item name="Low Quality - Mild Disrepair" number="2">The windows are relatively low quality.  They are in a state of mild disrepair.  Trimming and/or adjustment, hardware improvements, and weatherproofing improvements could be undertaken.  In practice, improvements are performed on an as needed basis.  Installing replacement windows may be the best long term approach.  In the interim, it is important that the window exteriors be well maintained to avoid rot or water infiltration.</item>
        <item name="Water Staining" number="3">Water staining was noted.  The cause for the staining should be determined and repairs undertaken, if necessary, to prevent structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Damage" number="4">ined</item>
        <item name="Window Painted Shut" number="5">The window(s) are painted shut.  Improvement can be undertaken to allow normal operation of the window.</item>
        <item name="Window Inoperative" number="6">The window(s) are inoperative. Improvement can be undertaken to allow normal operation of the window.</item>
        <item name="Window Cracked" number="7">The window(s) are cracked and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Window Broken" number="8">The window(s) are broken and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Missing Pane" number="9">The pane of glass is missing from the window should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Window Hardware Missing" number="10">Window hardware is missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Window Hardware Damaged" number="11">Window hardware is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Glass Non-Tempered" number="12">Safety glass etchings were not observed on the glass within the window(s).  This glass is required for windows close to the floor or in hazardous locations and is generally identified by an etching in the corner of the glass pane.</item>
        <item name="Lost Seal" number="13">The window(s) have lost their seal.  This has resulted in condensation developing between the panes of glass and can cause the glass to loose it’s insulating properties.  The glass should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Window Condensation" number="14">The windows show evidence of condensation.  This is not a major concern.  Controlling indoor humidity levels and/or improving window efficiency (if needed) would help to control this condition.</item>
        <item name="Window Screen(s) Damaged" number="15">The damaged screen(s) were found on the window(s) should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Window Screen(s) Missing" number="16">It may be desirable to replace window screens where missing.  The owner should be consulted regarding any screens that may be in storage.</item>
        <item name="Sash Cords Missing" number="17">Sash cords (the ropes that hold up the windows) are missing on windows.  Re-installation is necessary to ensure proper operation of the window.</item>
        <item name="Storm(s) Missing" number="18">Ideally, storm windows would be provided where missing.  The owner should be consulted regarding any storm windows that may be in storage.</item>
        <item name="Window Blocked Off" number="19">A window has been blocked off.  This should be investigated further to determine if it is weather proof.</item>
        <item name="Non Keyless Burglar Bars" number="20">Burglar bars were permanently attached over windows were egress is required.  Non-keyless operable burglar bars should be installed in these areas to improve the safety of the occupants.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-H" number="21">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to exhaustively observe insulated windows for evidence of broken seals; exhaustively observe glazing for identifying labels; or identify specific locations of damage.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="FIREPLACE / CHIMNEY COMMENTS" number="412">
        <item name="Poor Draft Evident" number="1">The fireplace shows evidence of having a poor draft.  There are a number of improvements that can be undertaken to alter this condition (if it proves to be a problem).  In some cases, it is not cost effective to improve the draft, and glass doors are installed to contain the smoke within the firebox.</item>
        <item name="Firebox Mortar Repair" number="2">The fireplace firebox mortar should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Firebox Rear Wall Repair" number="3">The rear wall of the fireplace firebox should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Firebox Rebuild" number="4">The fireplace firebox should be rebuilt for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Flue/Firebox Creosote" number="5">Significant creosote build up was noted in the fireplace flue and/or firebox. Cleaning of these areas should be undertaken for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Damper Operation" number="6">The fireplace damper does not operate and requires repair.</item>
        <item name="Damper Missing" number="7">The fireplace damper is missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Zero Clearance Firebox Bulging" number="8">Zero Clearance Firebox Bulging</item>
        <item name="Zero Clearance Poor Install" number="9">Zero Clearance Poor Install</item>
        <item name="Hearth Insufficient" number="10">The hearth outside the fireplace is not large enough to reduce the risk of fire, should hot embers manage to escape from the fireplace.  This situation should be altered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Hearth Damage" number="11">The hearth outside the fireplace is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Lintel Damage" number="12">The lintel for the fireplace is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Combustible Materials" number="13">Combustible materials were found to be to close to the fireplace.  These items should be moved or modified to improve safety.</item>
        <item name="Improve Glass Doors" number="14">The glass doors on the fireplace should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Fireplace Combustion Air" number="15">It is suspected that there is an insufficient supply of combustion air for the fireplace.  Improvement is usually straightforward, and should be considered high priority for safety reasons.</item>
        <item name="Fan Not Operating" number="16">The circulating fan for the fireplace was not operating and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Log Lighter Not Operating" number="17">The gas log lighter for the fireplace is not operating and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Log Lighter Gas Not On" number="18">No test of the gas log lighter for the fireplace was able to be performed since the gas was turned off.</item>
        <item name="Log Lighter Gas Leak" number="19">The log lighter for the fireplace was found to have an active gas leak.  This should be repaired immediately since it poses a safety hazard.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Normal Wear And Tear" number="20">The masonry chimney shows evidence of normal wear and tear.  No improvements are considered necessary.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Re-Pointing" number="21">The masonry chimney is in need of re-pointing (replacing the mortar between the bricks).</item>
        <item name="Masonry Minor Spalling - Watch" number="22">The masonry chimney shows evidence of spalling (surface deterioration of the masonry).  Improvement is not considered necessary at this time, although this condition should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Spall/Eventual Rebuild" number="23">The masonry chimney shows evidence of spalling (surface deterioration of the masonry).  Rebuilding of this chimney will ultimately be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Rebuilding Needed" number="24">The masonry chimney shows evidence of substantial deterioration.  Rebuilding is recommended.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Damaged Cap - Replace" number="25">The cap of the masonry chimney should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Rain Cap/Screen Needed" number="26">A rain cap and vermin screen should be installed on the masonry chimney.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Out Of Service/Remove?" number="27">The chimney is no longer in service.  It could be removed down to a level below the roof line.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Out Of Plumb" number="28">The masonry chimney is out of plumb.  This condition should be carefully monitored.  If it worsens, the chimney should be rebuilt.  In the interim, it would be wise to brace the chimney.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Bracing Needed" number="29">The masonry chimney should be braced in order to ensure its stability in heavy winds.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Flue Liner Cracked" number="30">The flue liner of the masonry chimney is cracked.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Insuff. Height/Clear." number="31">The masonry chimney should be altered to ensure that it is at least three(3) feet high and at least two(2) feet higher than any obstruction within ten feet.</item>
        <item name="Masonry Clean Flue" number="32">The masonry chimney should be cleaned.</item>
        <item name="Metal Chimney Surface Rust" number="33">The metal chimney is rusting.  It should be painted with an appropriate paint or repaired as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Substantial Rust/Insul. Chimney" number="34">The insulated metal chimney shows evidence of rusting.  This can pose a safety concern.  This condition should be investigated by a chimney specialist before continuing to use this chimney.  Deteriorated sections of the chimney should be replaced as needed.</item>
        <item name="Metal Chimney Bracing Needed" number="35">The metal chimney should be braced in order to ensure its stability in heavy winds.</item>
        <item name="Metal Chimney Damage" number="36">The metal chimney is damaged.  It should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Metal Chimney Cap Needed" number="37">The metal chimney requires a cap.</item>
        <item name="Vermin Screen Needed" number="38">A vermin screen should be installed on the metal chimney.</item>
        <item name="Metal Insuff. Height/Clearance" number="39">The metal chimney should be altered to ensure that it is at least three(3) feet high and at least two(2) feet higher than any obstruction within ten feet.</item>
        <item name="Metal Clean Flue" number="40">The metal chimney should be cleaned.</item>
        <item name="No Attic Firestopping" number="41">Firestopping was not present in the attic surrounding the chimney flue.  This should be installed immediately as this poses a fire hazard.</item>
        <item name="Spark Arrestor Damaged" number="42">The spark arrestor for the chimney is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Birds Nest" number="43">The birds nest should be removed from the chimney.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-J" number="44">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to verify the integrity of the flue; perform a chimney smoke test; or determine the adequacy of the draft.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="PORCH / DECK / CARPORT COMMENTS" number="413">
        <item name="Porch Settlement" number="1">The porch has settled relative to the house proper.  This is a common condition that should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Porch Column Movement" number="2">The porch columns show evidence of movement.  This is very typical for older homes.</item>
        <item name="Porch Masonry Spalling" number="3">The porch masonry is deteriorating noticeably.  Repairs or rebuilding may eventually be needed here.</item>
        <item name="Porch Rot" number="4">The porch shows evidence of rot.  Replacement may eventually be desired.  In the interim, localized repairs could be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Porch Wood/Soil Contact" number="5">Wood/soil contact at the porch should be avoided.</item>
        <item name="Porch Steps Settled" number="6">The steps serving the porch have settled somewhat.  If this condition persists, or if the steps become a trip hazard, improvements should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Porch Steps Rotted" number="7">The porch steps are rotting and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Porch Trip Hazard At Steps" number="8">The porch steps represent a trip hazard and should be repaired.  This is a safety concern that should be addressed promptly.</item>
        <item name="Porch Railing Loose" number="9">The porch railing is loose.  It is recommended that this be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Porch Railing Needed" number="10">As there is a danger of falling, a railing should be provided for the porch.</item>
        <item name="Porch Railing Openings" number="11">The openings in the porch railing are large enough to allow an object of 4 inches in diameter to fall through.  Repairs should be undertaken for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Porch Dilapidated" number="12">The porch is dilapidated.  It should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Deck Paint/Stain Needed" number="13">The deck should be painted or stained to improve durability.</item>
        <item name="Deck Rot" number="14">The deck shows evidence of rot.  Replacement may eventually be desired.  In the interim, localized repairs could be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Deck Built On Grade" number="15">The deck has been built at grade level.  Repairs should be undertaken as this configuration is prone to rot and insect activity.</item>
        <item name="Deck Low Quality Installation" number="16">The construction of the deck is low quality.  Replacement may be the best long term approach.</item>
        <item name="Deck Posts Not Well Supported" number="17">The support posts for the deck are not well founded and should be repaired.  Ideally, a footing extending at least 2 feet below grade level would be installed.  Wood/soil contact should be avoided.</item>
        <item name="Deck Steps Rotted" number="18">The deck steps are rotting and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Deck Trip Hazard At Steps" number="19">The deck steps represent a trip hazard and should be repaired.  This is a safety concern that should be addressed promptly.</item>
        <item name="Deck Railing Loose" number="20">The deck railing is loose.  It is recommended that this be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Deck Railing Needed" number="21">As there is a danger of falling, a railing should be provided for the deck.</item>
        <item name="Deck Railing Openings" number="22">The openings in the deck railing are large enough to allow an object of four inches in diameter to fall through.  It is recommended that this be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Deck Dilapidated" number="23">The deck is dilapidated.  It should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Post Rot" number="24">The bottoms of the support posts for the carport are rotted.  They should be re-supported.</item>
        <item name="Post Settlement" number="25">The foundation supporting the carport support posts has settled somewhat.  These posts should be re-supported.</item>
        <item name="Step Steep Pitch" number="26">The steps are relatively steep. It may not be practical to change this condition. Extreme care should be taken when using this stairway. Carelessness could lead to an accident.</item>
        <item name="Step Treads Non Standard" number="27">The size and/or orientation of the step "treads" may make the stairway difficult to negotiate.  This condition should be altered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Step Risers Non Standard" number="28">The size and/or orientation of the step "risers" may make the stairway difficult to negotiate.  This condition should be altered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Step Treads Damaged" number="29">The step treads were found to be damaged.  This condition should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Step Handrail Loose" number="30">Loose handrails for the steps should be better secured.</item>
        <item name="Step Handrail Needed" number="31">For improved safety, it is recommended that a railings be provided for the steps.</item>
        <item name="Step Railing Loose" number="32">The railing for the steps is loose and should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Step Railing Needed" number="33">For improved safety, it is recommended that a railing be provided for the steps.</item>
        <item name="Railing Loose" number="34">The railing is loose and should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Railing Needed" number="35">For improved safety, it is recommended that a railing be provided.</item>
        <item name="Railing Openings" number="36">The openings in the railing are large enough to allow an object larger than four inches to fall through. It is recommended that this condition be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Railing Height" number="37">The height of the railing may not be sufficient to prevent a person from toppling over the railing. It is recommended that this condition be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-K" number="38">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to exhaustively measure the porch, balcony, deck, or attach carport components; or enter any area where the headroom is less than 18 inches or the access opening is less than 24 inches wide and 18 inches high.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="STAIRWAY COMMENTS" number="414">
        <item name="Stair Steep Pitch" number="1">The stairway is relatively steep. It may not be practical to change this condition. Extreme care should be taken when using this stairway. Carelessness could lead to an accident.</item>
        <item name="Stair Treads Non Standard" number="2">The size and/or orientation of the stairway "treads" may make the stairway difficult to negotiate.  This condition should be altered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Stair Risers Non Standard" number="3">The size and/or orientation of the stairway "risers" may make the stairway difficult to negotiate.  This condition should be altered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Stair Treads Loose" number="4">The stair treads were found to be loose.  This condition should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Stair Treads Damaged" number="5">The stair treads were found to be damaged.  This condition should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Curved Stair Tread Non Standard" number="6">The size and/or orientation of the curved stairway "treads" may make the stairway difficult to negotiate.  This condition should be altered for improved safety. In some cases, improvement is not cost effective.</item>
        <item name="Door Opens Into Stairwell" number="7">The door at the top of the stairwell should open away from the stairs. It is recommended that this door be altered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Spiral Stairway Unsafe" number="8">The spiral staircase is difficult to get down quickly and is thereby  dangerous in the event of a fire.  In most areas, these types of stairways are not permitted as the only means by which to get from one floor to another.</item>
        <item name="Missing Handrail" number="9">The handrail was observed to be missing in the stairwell. For improved safety, it is recommended that a handrail be installed.</item>
        <item name="Loose Railing" number="10">The railing / guards for the stairway is loose and should be better secured for reasons of safety.</item>
        <item name="Non-Continuous Railing" number="11">The stairway handrail does not run continuous from the bottom of the stairwell to the top of the stairwell so to cover all of the steps (treads). Under current building standards all handrails for the stairway should run continuous for the full length of the flight. The handrail should start directly above the lowest step and run continuously to end directly above the top step.</item>
        <item name="Spindles to Far Apart" number="12">The stairwell balusters and/or spindles are installed to far apart. Under current building standards the required guardrails on open sides of stairways, raised floor areas, balconies and porches should have intermediate rails or ornamental closures which do not allow passage of an object more than 4-inches</item>
        <item name="Not Enough Headroom" number="13">There does not appear to be enough headroom in the stairwell. Under current building standards the minimum headroom in all parts of the stairway shall not be less than 6 feet 8 inches measured vertically from the slope of the plane adjoining the tread nosing or from the floor surface of the landing or platform</item>
        <item name="Bad Light switch location" number="14">The light switch for the stairway is poorly located.  Under current standards, the activation switch should be accessible at the top and bottom of the stairway without traversing any step of the stairs.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-I" number="15">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to exhaustively measure every stairway component.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="SERVICE ENTRANCE / PANELS COMMENTS" number="416">
        <item name="Undersized Service" number="1">The electrical service is undersized.  It should be upgraded to at least 100 amps.</item>
        <item name="Tap On Main Service" number="2">Any distribution wiring connected directly to the main service should be removed.  All household circuits should be connected to a distribution panel where they can be protected by fuses or breakers.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Wires" number="3">Damaged or frayed service wires should be repaired or replaced as needed.</item>
        <item name="Drip Loop Insufficient" number="4">The service wires should form a "drip loop" where they meet the service mast on the exterior of the home.  This should be repaired to ensure that water will drip off the wires, rather than run into the service mast.</item>
        <item name="Clearance Inadequate" number="5">The service wires do not have adequate clearance from the ground and should be repaired.  The top of the service mast and the service wires should be at least fifteen (15) feet from the ground.</item>
        <item name="Poorly Attached/Loose" number="6">The service mast/conduit should be better secured to the exterior of the home.</item>
        <item name="Undersized Service Box" number="7">The undersized main service box should be replaced, unless it is approved by the local electrical utility.</item>
        <item name="Rusted Service Box" number="8">The service box shows evidence of rusting, suggesting the presence of moisture.  This area should be monitored.  If rusting continues, or if moisture is evident in the vicinity of the service box, an electrician should be consulted.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Service Box" number="9">The damaged service box should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Grounding Ineffective" number="10">The grounding of the electrical service is ineffective.  The service should be grounded to the main water supply and/or driven ground rods as required.</item>
        <item name="No Meter Bypass" number="11">A jumper wire should be installed across the water meter to ensure sufficient grounding of the electrical service.  Alternatively, the ground wire could be connected to the water main, upstream of the water meter.</item>
        <item name="Obsolete Panel" number="12">The main distribution panel is obsolete and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Undersized Panel" number="13">The main distribution panel is undersized.  It should be replaced with a panel that is suitable to the size of the incoming service.</item>
        <item name="Location Inappropriate" number="14">The main distribution panel should be moved to an appropriate location.</item>
        <item name="Capacity Insufficient" number="15">The main distribution panel does not contain enough circuits to properly serve the home.  A larger panel or an auxiliary would be desirable.</item>
        <item name="Oversized Fuses" number="16">Oversized fuses within the main distribution panel should be replaced.  All fuses serving household branch circuits should be sized at fifteen (15) amps.</item>
        <item name="Oversized Breakers" number="17">Oversized breakers within the main distribution panel should be replaced.  All breakers serving household branch circuits should be sized at fifteen (15) amps.</item>
        <item name="Openings In Panel" number="18">Any openings in the main panel should be covered.</item>
        <item name="Cover Missing" number="19">The main panel cover plate (sometimes called the "Dead Front") is missing.  It should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Panel" number="20">The main distribution panel is damaged and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Rusted Panel" number="21">The main distribution panel shows evidence of rusting, suggesting the presence of moisture.  This area should be monitored.  If rusting continues, or if moisture is evident in the vicinity of the panel, an electrician should be consulted.</item>
        <item name="No Disconnect" number="22">The main distribution panel did not have a disconnect.  This item should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Double Taps" number="23">Circuits within the main distribution panel that are doubled up (referred to as "double taps") should be separated.  Each circuit should be served by a separate fuse or breaker.</item>
        <item name="Crowded" number="24">The main distribution panel is crowded with wiring.  A larger panel, or an auxiliary panel, would be desirable.</item>
        <item name="Linking/Bridging Missing" number="25">Linking (sometimes referred to as bridging) should be provided wherever two fuses or breakers serve the same circuit.  This ensures that the entire circuit is shut off whenever a fuse is pulled, or a breaker is tripped.  Linking is required, for example, on circuits serving kitchen split receptacles, baseboard heaters and any 240 volt appliance.</item>
        <item name="Overheated Wiring" number="26">Overheated wiring within the main distribution panel should be examined by a licensed electrician and repaired as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Poor Connections" number="27">Poor electrical connections within the main distribution panel should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Cable Clamps Needed" number="28">Cable clamps (sometimes referred to as bushings or grommets) are required where wiring passes into the main distribution panel.  Cable clamps serve to protect the wiring from the metal edges of the panel openings.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations II-A" number="29">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to determine present or future sufficiency of service capacity amperage, voltage, or the capacity of the electrical system; test arc-fault circuit interrupter devices when the property is occupied or damage to personal property may result, in the inspector’s reasonable judgment; report the lack of arc-fault circuit interrupter protection when the circuits are in conduit; conduct voltage drop calculations; determine the accuracy of overcurrent devices labeling; remove covers where hazardous as judged by the inspector; verify the effectiveness of overcurrent devices; or operate overcurrent devices.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="BRANCH CIRCUITS/DEVICES/FIXTURES" number="417">
        <item name="Wiring: Abandoned" number="1">Abandoned wiring should be replaced or appropriately terminated.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Damaged" number="2">Damaged wiring should be replaced or appropriately repaired.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Loose" number="3">Loose wiring should be secured.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Overheating" number="4">Overheated wiring should be repaired or replaced as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Exposed On Walls" number="5">Wiring exposed on interior finishes should be relocated or protected by a rigid conduit.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Touching Ducts/Pipes" number="6">Wiring should not touch hot air ductwork or hot water piping.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Undersized" number="7">Undersized wiring should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Inappropriate For Ext." number="8">The exterior wiring is not suited to this application.  It should be replaced with wiring suitable for outdoor use.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Extension Cords" number="9">Extension cords should not be used as permanent wiring.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Poor Connections" number="10">Improper electrical connections should be improved.  All electrical connections should be made inside junction boxes fitted with cover plates.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Junction Boxes Loose" number="11">Loose junction boxes should be properly secured.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Junction Box CVR Plates" number="12">All junction boxes should be fitted with cover plates, in order to protect the wire connections.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Amateur Installation" number="13">The installation of the distribution wiring is non-standard.  It is suspected that installation was performed by an amateur, rather than a licensed electrician.</item>
        <item name="No Bonding On Appliances" number="14">Bonding was not found on appliances.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety hazard.</item>
        <item name="Sub Panel Location" number="15">The electrical sub panel should be moved to an appropriate location.</item>
        <item name="Sub Panel Ground/Bond" number="16">The electrical sub panel does not appear to be properly grounded/bonded.  This should be investigated and repaired.</item>
        <item name="Sub Panel Disconnect" number="17">The electrical sub panel did not have a disconnect.  This item should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Inapp. Outlets And Connectors" number="18">The aluminum wiring should be fitted with special connectors and outlets to ensure safe operation of these circuits.  During installation of this special hardware, all connections should be checked for signs of damage or overheating.  It should be pointed out that the aluminum wiring itself is a perfectly acceptable electrical conductor.  The connection points can experience overheating or become loose due to the properties of aluminum wiring.  Upon fitting the wiring with the special connectors and outlets, the wiring is considered to be safe.</item>
        <item name="Aluminum Wiring: Overheating" number="19">The aluminum wiring shows signs of overheating and should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="Alum. Wiring: Panel Not Rated" number="20">The main distribution panel does not appear to be rated for use with aluminum wiring, although there is aluminum wiring present.  This should be investigated and/or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Inoperative" number="21">An outlet is inoperative.  This outlet and circuit should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Inoperative" number="22">An outlet is inoperative.  This outlet and circuit should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Damaged" number="23">An outlet is damaged.  It should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Loose" number="24">An outlet is loose and should be re-secured.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Reversed Polarity" number="25">An outlet has reversed polarity (i.e. it is wired backwards).  This outlet and the circuit should be investigated and improved as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Ungrounded 3-Prong" number="26">Ungrounded 3-prong outlets should be improved.  This can be as simple as filling the ground slot with epoxy.  Alternatively, a grounded cable could be strung to this outlet, or a separate ground wire could be connected.  Some electrical codes allow the installation of a ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) type outlet where grounding is not provided.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Overheated" number="27">An outlet has overheated.  This outlet should be replaced and the circuit should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: GFCI Test Faulty" number="28">A ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) outlet did not respond correctly to testing during the inspection.  This receptacle should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: GFCI Inoperative" number="29">A ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) outlet is inoperative.  This circuit should be investigated and/or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: GFCI Recommended" number="30">The installation of a ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) is recommended.  A ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI)  offers protection from shock or electrocution.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Cover Plates" number="31">Missing outlet cover plates should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Inoperative" number="32">The inoperative light switch should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Damaged" number="33">The damaged light switch should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Loose" number="34">The loose light switch should be secured.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Obsolete" number="35">The older light switches are obsolete and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Overheated" number="36">The light switch shows evidence of overheating.  This circuit should be investigated and the switch should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Inoperative" number="37">The light is inoperative.  If the bulbs are not blown, the circuit should be investigated.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Damaged" number="38">The damaged light fixture should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Loose" number="39">The loose light fixture should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Recessed Light Bulbs" number="40">Recessed lights should be fitted with bulbs suitable to this application.  Otherwise, there is a risk of overheating and/or fire.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Recessed Light Rating" number="41">Recessed light fixtures that are installed in insulated ceilings can represent a fire hazard if they are not suitably rated for this application.  Unfortunately, it is difficult to verify that the installation has been made safely, during a home inspection.  It is recommended that a licensed electrician be engaged to verify the safety of the system.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Supported By Wiring" number="42">Light fixtures should not be supported by wiring.</item>
        <item name="Ceiling Fan Inoperative" number="43">A ceiling fan is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Smoke Detector Inoperative" number="44">A smoke detector is inoperative.  This item should be repaired as it poses a potential safety hazard.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations II-B" number="45">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to inspect low voltage wiring; disassemble mechanical appliances; verify the effectiveness of smoke alarms; verify the interconnectivity of smoke alarms; activate smoke alarms that are being actively monitored or require the use of codes; or verify that smoke alarms are suitable for the hearing-impaired.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="HEATING EQUIPMENT COMMENTS" number="418">
        <item name="Heating System Inoperative" number="1">The furnace was found to be inoperative using the normal control devices.  This should be investigated further and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Near End Of Life Cycle" number="2">Given the age of the furnace, it may be nearing the end of its useful life.  It would be wise to budget for a new furnace.</item>
        <item name="Replacement Imminent" number="3">Given the age of the furnace, replacement should be anticipated in the near future.</item>
        <item name="Premature Failure??" number="4">This particular make of furnace is prone to premature failure of the heat exchanger.  If the heat exchanger cracks or deteriorates prematurely, replacement of the heat exchanger (or the entire furnace depending of the availability of parts) will be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Octopus - Replace ASAP" number="5">It is recommended that the old "octopus" furnace be replaced.  These older systems can pose a heath risk if the heat exchanger has failed.  The improved efficiency of a new furnace would begin to offset the cost of installation immediately.  Ductwork modifications will be necessary when the furnace is upgraded.</item>
        <item name="Location Unsafe" number="6">The location of the furnace is considered unsafe.  This situation can pose a health threat and may also be a fire hazard.  A qualified heating technician should be engaged immediately to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Cracked Heat Exchanger Observed" number="7">The furnace heat exchanger was observed to cracked.  This condition is a potential health threat that should be further evaluated and/or repaired.  A qualified service technician or utility company representative should be engaged immediately.</item>
        <item name="Furnace Inaccessible" number="8">The furnace was inaccessible and could not be inspected.</item>
        <item name="Servicing Needed" number="9">The heating system requires servicing.</item>
        <item name="Blower/Motor Suspect" number="10">The blower and motor serving the heating system are in suspect condition.  This should be monitored and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Humidifier Replacement" number="11">The humidifier should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Humidifier Maintenance" number="12">The humidifier has lacked maintenance somewhat.  Cleaning and repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Air Filter Dirty" number="13">The dirty air filter should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Electronic Air Cleaner Dirty" number="14">The electronic air cleaner requires cleaning.</item>
        <item name="Elect. Air Cleaner Not Working" number="15">The electronic air cleaner did not appear to the functioning at the time of inspection.  This should be investigated and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Line Dirty" number="16">The condensate line leading from the furnace appears dirty.  This condition should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Pump Inoperative" number="17">The furnace condensate pump is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Fan Limit Adjustment" number="18">The fan limit switch appears to require adjustment.</item>
        <item name="Fan Limit Inoperative" number="19">The fan limit switch did not respond properly upon testing.  This represents a potential safety concern and should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Condensation/Vent Problems" number="20">As with many homes that are electrically heated, there is evidence of condensation and ventilation difficulties.  This condition should be monitored and/or repaired.  If this proves to be a problem, steps should be taken to better control humidity and improve air change within the house.  This could be as simple as installing exhaust fans.  A more sophisticated measure would be to install a heat recovery ventilator.</item>
        <item name="Combustion Air Lacking" number="21">The supply of combustion air (and draft air) for the heating system may be insufficient.  This condition represents a health hazard that should be investigated and/or repaired immediately.  Additional combustion air can usually be provided without a great deal of difficulty or expense.</item>
        <item name="Burner Old" number="22">The burner is older.  It is difficult to predict the useful remaining life of this unit.</item>
        <item name="Burner Suspect" number="23">The burner is in suspect condition.  It should be evaluated by a qualified licensed heating technician and improved as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Burner Dirty/Soot" number="24">Soot build up and debris were observed on or around the burner.  Cleaning and servicing are recommended.</item>
        <item name="Burner Rust" number="25">The burner shows evidence of corrosion.  This condition should be evaluated and/or repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Deposits" number="26">There was a noticeable quantity of deposits visible in the gas furnace.  This is a residue from the reaction of gas combustion and galvanized steel.  These deposits are not unusual but can be an indication of lack of periodic cleaning and maintenance.</item>
        <item name="Flashback" number="27">The heating system shows evidence of "flashback" (ignited gas spilling out at the front of the furnace at start up).  This condition should be evaluated and/or repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Pilot Problems?" number="28">Evidence suggests that problems have been experienced in past with the pilot light. This condition should be evaluated and/or repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Back Drafting" number="29">The heating system shows evidence that exhaust products have been "back drafting".  This is a health concern and should be repaired immediately.  This condition may be the result of insufficient combustion/draft air, inappropriate flue and chimney configuration, obstructions within the chimney or exhaust flue, or a problem with the furnace itself.  A qualified licensed heating technician should be consulted.</item>
        <item name="Gas Line Material" number="30">Inappropriate material is being used for the furnace gas lines.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Gas Valve Location" number="31">A valve for the furnace gas line is in an inappropriate location.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="No Gas Shut-Off" number="32">No shut-off for the furnace gas line was found.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Furnace Gas Leak" number="33">A leak was detected in the furnace gas lines.  This should be repaired immediately as it poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative Heater" number="34">The baseboard heater was found to be inoperative using the normal control devices.  This should be investigated further and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="No Source of Heat" number="35">No heat source was found.  It may be desirable to install a baseboard heater in this location.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Heater" number="36">A damaged heater was observed.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Rusted Heater" number="37">Baseboard heater(s) show evidence of corrosion. Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Control Damaged" number="38">Baseboard heater controls are damaged and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Old Heaters" number="39">The baseboard heaters are older.  Their reliability may be reduced.  Replacement units may be necessary over time.</item>
        <item name="Wiring Unsafe" number="40">Unsafe electric heater wiring was observed.  For safety reasons, this should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations III-A" number="41">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to program digital thermostats or controls; inspect for pressure of the system refrigerant, type of refrigerant, type of refrigerant, or refrigerant leaks; winterized evaporative coolers; or humidifiers, dehumidifiers, air purifiers, motorized dampers, electronic air filters, multi-stage controllers, sequencers, heat reclaimers, wood burning stove, boilers, oil-fired units, supplemental heating appliances, de-icing provisions, or reversing values; operate setback features on thermostats, or controls; cooling equipment when the outdoor temperature is less than 60 degrees Fahrenheit; radiant heaters, steam heat systems, or unvented gas-fired heating appliances; or heat pumps when temperatures may damage equipment; verify compatibility of components; the accuracy of thermostats; or the integrity of the heat exchanger; or determine sizing, efficiency, or adequacy of the system; uniformity of the supply of conditioned air to the various parts of the structure; or types of materials contained in insulations.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="COOLING EQUIPMENT COMMENTS" number="419">
        <item name="Inoperative System" number="1">The air conditioning system was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate of this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Old System" number="2">As is not uncommon for homes of this age and location, the air conditioning system is older.  It may require a slightly higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to major component breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.</item>
        <item name="Very Old System" number="3">As is not uncommon for homes of this age and location, the air conditioning system is relatively old.  It will require a higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to major component breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.  If the compressor fails, or if breakdowns become chronic, replacing the entire system may be more cost-effective than continuing to undertake repairs.</item>
        <item name="System Obsolete" number="4">The air conditioning system is obsolete and should be replaced (assuming central air conditioning is desired).</item>
        <item name="Undersized System?" number="5">The capacity of the air conditioning system may prove to be marginal during the warmer days of the summer.  Without performing detailed heat gain calculations, or living in the home during warm summer days, actual conditions are difficult to predict.  No improvements are recommended at this time.</item>
        <item name="Temperature Drop Excessive" number="6">The temperature drop measured across the evaporator coil of the air conditioning system is greater than considered normal.  This indicates that air flow across the evaporator coil is too low.  Low air flow could be the result of a dirty filter, dirty or obstructed evaporator coil fins, or insufficient blower and/or ductwork sizing.  This condition can lead to ice build-up on the coil.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Temperature Drop Insufficient" number="7">The temperature drop measured across the evaporator coil of the air conditioning system is lower than considered typical.  This usually indicates that servicing is needed.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Service Needed" number="8">The air conditioning system requires servicing.</item>
        <item name="Insulation Damage On Ref. Lines" number="9">Damaged insulation on refrigerant lines should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Return Chase Location" number="10">The return chase/vent for the air conditioning system is in an improper location.  This vent should be situated away from any gas pipes, sewer vents, refrigerant piping or electrical wiring.</item>
        <item name="Outdoor Unit Out Of Level" number="11">The outdoor unit of the air conditioning system is out of level.  This should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Outdoor Unit Dirty" number="12">The outdoor unit of the air conditioning system requires cleaning.</item>
        <item name="Outdoor Unit Fin Damage" number="13">The fins of the outdoor portion of the air conditioning system were observed to be damaged and in need of repair.  This condition can reduce the efficiency of the system.</item>
        <item name="Outdoor Unit Noisy" number="14">The outdoor unit of the air conditioning system is noisy.  This should be investigated during servicing.</item>
        <item name="Cut Back Vegetation" number="15">Vegetation in the vicinity of the outdoor unit of the air conditioning system should be cut back.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Tray Leak" number="16">Evidence of prior leakage was observed at the condensate tray of the air conditioning system.  Repairs should be undertaken, if necessary</item>
        <item name="Cond. Discharge Location Poor" number="17">The discharge location of the condensate line for the air conditioning system should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Line Blocked" number="18">The air conditioning condensate line appears to be obstructed.  Minor improvements are needed.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative Condensate Pump" number="19">The condensate pump was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  Further investigation and/or repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Trap Needed" number="20">Condensate lines for air conditioning systems that flow into sanitary drains should be "trapped" to avoid the potential for contamination.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Line Insulation" number="21">Damaged insulation on condensate lines should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Drip Pan Needed" number="22">In order to reduce the potential for water damage, it is recommended that an auxiliary drain pan be installed below the indoor component of the air conditioning system.</item>
        <item name="Drip Pan Undersized" number="23">The auxiliary drain pan installed below the of the air conditioning system is undersized and should be repaired</item>
        <item name="Drip Pan Water/Debris" number="24">The auxiliary drain pan installed below the of the air conditioning system contains water and debris.  This should be emptied and cleaned.</item>
        <item name="Indoor Fan Noisy/Vibrates" number="25">The indoor fan is excessively noisy.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Indoor Fan Undersized?" number="26">The indoor fan may be undersized.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Electrical Conductor Size" number="27">The electrical service for the air conditioning unit is undersized and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Over Current Protection" number="28">The over current protection for the air conditioning unit is undersized and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="One Speed" number="29">The evaporative cooler is a one speed model.</item>
        <item name="Two Speed" number="30">The evaporative cooler is a two speed model.</item>
        <item name="Lacking Maintenance" number="31">The evaporative cooler has been lacking maintenance somewhat.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Older System" number="32">As is not uncommon for homes of this age and location, the evaporative cooler is older.  It may require a higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to component breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.</item>
        <item name="Obsolete Unit" number="33">The evaporative cooler is obsolete and should be replaced (assuming air conditioning is desired).</item>
        <item name="Inoperative Cooler" number="34">The evaporative cooler was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Noisy Motor" number="35">The motor serving the evaporative cooler is noisy.   A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Housing Damaged" number="36">The exterior housing of the evaporative cooler is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Fan Belt/Pulley Repair" number="37">The fan belt/pulleys within the evaporative cooler are damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Fan Rust" number="38">The rust is being built up within the evaporative cooler and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Water Supply Line" number="39">The water supply line for the evaporative cooler is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Air Gap Too Small" number="40">The air gap between the water level and float in the evaporative cooler is too small (a minimum  of a one inch air gap is required).  This item should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Float Valve Suspect" number="41">The float valve for the evaporative cooler is in suspect condition.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Spray Nozzle Restricted" number="42">The evaporative cooler spray nozzle appears to be restricted and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Pump Suspect" number="43">The pump for the evaporative cooler is in suspect condition.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Water Pads/Blankets Dirty" number="44">The water pads/blanket utilized by the evaporative cooler are dirty and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Roof Jacks Marginal" number="45">The roof jacks are in marginal condition.  Improvement will likely be necessary over the next few years.</item>
        <item name="Roof Jacks Poor" number="46">The roof jacks are in poor condition.  A qualified licensed contractor should be contacted to evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Excess Humidity In House" number="47">Operation of the evaporative cooler appears to have resulted in excess humidity on the interior of the home.  A qualified licensed contractor should be contacted to evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Loose Thermostat" number="48">The thermostat should be better secured and leveled.</item>
        <item name="Old" number="49">The thermostat is older and may prove to be temperamental.  Replacement is a minor job.</item>
        <item name="Location" number="50">The location of the thermostat is less than ideal.  It may be subject to inconsistent temperatures.  Relocating the thermostat is a minor job.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations III-B" number="51">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to program digital thermostats or controls; inspect for pressure of the system refrigerant, type of refrigerant, type of refrigerant, or refrigerant leaks; winterized evaporative coolers; or humidifiers, dehumidifiers, air purifiers, motorized dampers, electronic air filters, multi-stage controllers, sequencers, heat reclaimers, wood burning stove, boilers, oil-fired units, supplemental heating appliances, de-icing provisions, or reversing values; operate setback features on thermostats, or controls; cooling equipment when the outdoor temperature is less than 60 degrees Fahrenheit; radiant heaters, steam heat systems, or unvented gas-fired heating appliances; or heat pumps when temperatures may damage equipment; verify compatibility of components; the accuracy of thermostats; or the integrity of the heat exchanger; or determine sizing, efficiency, or adequacy of the system; uniformity of the supply of conditioned air to the various parts of the structure; or types of materials contained in insulations.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="DUCTS / VENTS COMMENTS" number="420">
        <item name="Low Flow" number="1">Supply air flow is considered less than ideal.  Rebalancing the ductwork may improve this situation.</item>
        <item name="Balancing Needed" number="2">Balancing of the ductwork is recommended to improve the distribution.</item>
        <item name="Proximity Of Furnace Poor" number="3">The proximity of the furnace to the ductwork is such that air flow to certain areas of the home will be less than ideal.</item>
        <item name="Duct Cleaning Needed" number="4">Duct cleaning is recommended.</item>
        <item name="Seal Opening" number="5">Loose fitting joints and/or openings in the ductwork should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Old Ducts Undersized" number="6">As is common in older homes, the ductwork is not ideally configured.  This may inhibit distribution slightly, and may not be conducive to proper distribution of cool air, if air conditioning is employed.</item>
        <item name="Rusted Ducts Below Slab" number="7">The ductwork installed below the concrete slab shows evidence of rusting.  This would suggest the presence of moisture in the ducts, which can also be a health hazard.  It is impossible to predict the condition of the ducts below the slab.  It may ultimately become necessary to abandon these ducts in favor of another means of heat distribution.</item>
        <item name="Motorized Dampers Suspect" number="8">Motorized dampers have been provided in the ductwork.  These dampers are typically operated by thermostats in different areas of the home.  The dampers open as the thermostats call for heat.  Most motorized damper systems are neglected over time and eventually break down.  They are often abandoned.</item>
        <item name="Improper Duct Material" number="9">The material being used for the ducts is inappropriate and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Duct Routing" number="10">The routing of the ductwork could be re-configured as it is now prone to potential damage.</item>
        <item name="No Return Air Vent At" number="11">No return air vent is visible.  Installing a return air vent in this location is not considered critical; however, it would improve heat distribution, and facilitate better cooling (if air conditioning is utilized).</item>
        <item name="No Return Flow" number="12">No return air flow was detectable from the vent.  This would suggest that the return air passageway is obstructed.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Return Vent Near Furnace" number="13">A return vent is situated relatively close to the furnace.  This arrangement is a safety concern, as it may be conducive to back drafting of the furnace exhaust.  Improvement is a minor task and should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Improper Duct Material" number="14">The material being used for the ducts is inappropriate and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Duct Routing" number="15">The routing of the ductwork could be re-configured as it is now prone to potential damage.</item>
        <item name="Flue Connections" number="16">Poor exhaust flue connections should be repaired immediately.</item>
        <item name="Vent Material Inappropriate" number="17">The exhaust vent material appears to be inappropriate to this application.  This condition should be repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Flue Slope" number="18">The slope of the exhaust flue does not appear to be sufficient to allow the safe flow of exhaust gases.  This condition should be evaluated and repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Flue Clearance" number="19">There is insufficient clearance between the exhaust flue and combustible materials.  This is a fire hazard.  This condition should be evaluated and repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Flue Termination Improper" number="20">The termination of the exhaust flue is improper.  This is a fire hazard.  This condition should be repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Induced Draft Fan Suspect" number="21">The induced draft fan serving the heating system is in suspect condition.  These fans have a reputation for breakdown.</item>
        <item name="Barometric Damper Improvement" number="22">The barometric damper on the exhaust flue requires improvement to ensure safe emission of exhaust products.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations III-C" number="23">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to program digital thermostats or controls; inspect for pressure of the system refrigerant, type of refrigerant, type of refrigerant, or refrigerant leaks; winterized evaporative coolers; or humidifiers, dehumidifiers, air purifiers, motorized dampers, electronic air filters, multi-stage controllers, sequencers, heat reclaimers, wood burning stove, boilers, oil-fired units, supplemental heating appliances, de-icing provisions, or reversing values; operate setback features on thermostats, or controls; cooling equipment when the outdoor temperature is less than 60 degrees Fahrenheit; radiant heaters, steam heat systems, or unvented gas-fired heating appliances; or heat pumps when temperatures may damage equipment; verify compatibility of components; the accuracy of thermostats; or the integrity of the heat exchanger; or determine sizing, efficiency, or adequacy of the system; uniformity of the supply of conditioned air to the various parts of the structure; or types of materials contained in insulations.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="WATER SUPPLY / FIXTURES COMMENTS" number="421">
        <item name="Pressure Regulator Needed" number="1">As the static water pressure of the supply plumbing system exceeds 80 pounds per square inch (psi), it would be wise to install a pressure regulator.  Otherwise, the plumbing system may be prone to leaks in piping, fittings or other equipment.</item>
        <item name="Older Steel" number="2">The older steel piping is subject to corrosion on the interior of the pipe.  As corrosion builds up, the inside diameter of the pipe becomes constricted, resulting in a loss of water pressure.  This piping is typically replaced when the loss of pressure can no longer be tolerated.</item>
        <item name="Leak" number="3">The supply piping is leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Exterior Corrosion" number="4">Corrosion on the exterior of the supply piping was observed.</item>
        <item name="Support Lacking" number="5">The supply pipe lacks adequate support and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Water Pressure Low" number="6">Water pressure was found to be low when tested with two fixtures operated simultaneously.  This condition should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Handle Missing" number="7">A supply valve handle is missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Handle Damaged" number="8">The installation of the supply piping is not workmanlike and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Pipe Hammer" number="9">Water hammer in the supply piping was observed when operating plumbing fixtures.  Over time, this condition can influence the integrity of pipe connections.  Closing valves and faucets slowly is one approach to avoiding water hammer.  Better securing pipes (where possible) and installing air chambers (shock absorbers) at the risers to fixtures would be another solution.</item>
        <item name="Workmanship Marginal" number="10">The installation of the supply piping is not workmanlike.</item>
        <item name="Condensation On Cold Pipe" number="11">If condensation of the cold water piping becomes a problem, this piping could be insulated.</item>
        <item name="Cross Connection" number="12">A "cross connection" was observed.  A cross connection exists whenever there is potential for potable water to contact a source of contamination.  This condition should be repaired as is poses a potential health concern.</item>
        <item name="Softened Water As Drink. Water" number="13">It is advised that drinking water supply piping bypass the water softener.  Sodium rich water can be harmful to plants and to your health.</item>
        <item name="Well Pump Older" number="14">The water pump is older.  As with any older mechanical device, it is impossible to predict its useful remaining life.</item>
        <item name="Pump/Tank Poor Setup" number="15">The water pump and pressure tank configuration are makeshift at best.  Improvement is advisable.</item>
        <item name="Waterlogged Holding Tank?" number="16">It is suspected that the pressure tank serving the water pump is "waterlogged".  Servicing is needed.</item>
        <item name="Older Fixtures" number="17">The majority of plumbing fixtures are older.</item>
        <item name="Poor Quality Installation" number="18">The installation of the plumbing fixtures has been performed in a non workmanlike fashion and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Hot/Cold Reversed" number="19">The hot and cold faucets are reversed and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Leaky" number="20">The faucet(s) are leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Loose" number="21">The faucet is loose and should be tightened.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Stiff" number="22">The faucet is stiff and should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Inoperative" number="23">The faucet is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Faucets Aging" number="24">The faucets are showing signs of age.  Updating faucets over time should be anticipated.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Mineral Build Up" number="25">Mineral build up was observed at faucets.  This may suggest "hard" water.  Continued build up at faucets and within pipes could affect the performance of the supply plumbing system.  Water conditioning equipment could be considered.  This situation should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Sink Damaged" number="26">The sink is damaged and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Sink Cracked" number="27">The sink is cracked and needs repair.</item>
        <item name="Sink Drains Slow" number="28">The sink was observed to drain slowly, suggesting that an obstruction may exist.</item>
        <item name="Sink Stopper Missing" number="29">The drainstop for the sink is missing and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Sink Stopper Inoperative" number="30">The drainstop for the sink is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Loose" number="31">The toilet is loose and should be re-secured.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Prior Leak" number="32">The toilet shows evidence of prior leakage.  This should be investigated to determine if any structural damage has occurred or whether the leak is still active.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Floor Damage" number="33">The floor adjacent to the toilet shows evidence of water damage.  This condition should be repaired before further structural damage occurs.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Cracked" number="34">The toilet is cracked and should, ideally, be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Slow Flush" number="35">The toilet was observed to flush slowly at the time of the inspection.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Inoperative" number="36">The toilet is inoperative and should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Runs On" number="37">The toilet runs on after flushing.  Improvement to the tank mechanism is likely to be needed.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Old" number="38">The toilet is old.  Replacement may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Shower Head Leak" number="39">The shower head is leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Shower Head Poor" number="40">The shower head is in poor condition.  Replacement may become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Tile Grout/Caulk" number="41">Cracked, deteriorated and/or missing shower stall grout and caulk should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Tile Damage" number="42">The tile shower stall requires repair.  Loose or damaged tile, grout and caulk should be repaired or replaced as necessary.  Any damage to the wall behind the tile should also be repaired (if necessary).  Further investigation may reveal the need to rebuild a portion of the shower stall.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Rebuild Tile Base" number="43">The base of the shower stall should be rebuilt.  Wall or floor damage beneath the enclosure should also be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Complete Rebuild" number="44">The shower stall should be rebuilt.  Replacement with an acrylic or fiberglass unit should be considered.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Drains Slow" number="45">The shower stall was observed to drain slowly, suggesting that an obstruction may exist.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Leak" number="46">The shower enclosure was found to be leaking.  This should be repaired before water damage to the structure occurs.</item>
        <item name="Shower Door Defective" number="47">The shower stall door is defective and should be repaired or replaced as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Bathtub Tile Grout And Caulk" number="48">Cracked, deteriorated and/or missing bathtub enclosure grout and caulk should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Bathtub Enclosure Caulk" number="49">Cracked, deteriorated and/or missing bathtub enclosure caulk should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Bathtub Enclosure Leak" number="50">The bathtub enclosure was found to be leaking.  This should be repaired before water damage to the structure occurs.</item>
        <item name="Bathtub Tile Damage" number="51">The tile bathtub enclosure requires repair.  Loose or damaged tile, grout and caulk should be repaired or replaced as necessary.  Any damage to the wall behind the tile should also be repaired (if necessary).</item>
        <item name="Bathtub Tile Rebuild" number="52">The bathtub enclosure should be rebuilt.  Wall damage behind the enclosure should also be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Bathtub: Floor Spill Damage" number="53">Evidence of water damage to the floor adjacent to the bathtub enclosure was observed.  The extent of damage is difficult to predict without removing floor coverings.  Repairs are not high priority, but may eventually be desired.</item>
        <item name="Bathtub Window In Enclosure" number="54">The window and sill of the bathtub enclosure should be protected from moisture.  A waterproof curtain is usually sufficient.  Windows in bathtub enclosures have a reputation for allowing leakage behind the enclosure, causing damage to the wall.</item>
        <item name="Bathtub Drains Slow" number="55">The bathtub was observed to drain slowly, suggesting that an obstruction may exist.</item>
        <item name="Bathtub Stopper Missing" number="56">The drainstop for the tub is missing and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Bathtub Stopper Inoperative" number="57">The drainstop for the tub is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Bidet Loose" number="58">The bidet is loose and should be re-secured.</item>
        <item name="Bidet Prior Leak" number="59">The bidet shows evidence of prior leakage. This should be investigated to determine if any structural damage has occurred or whether the leak is still active.</item>
        <item name="Bidet Cracked" number="60">The bidet is cracked and should, ideally, be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Bidet Slow Drain" number="61">The bidet was observed to drain slowly, suggesting that an obstruction may exist.</item>
        <item name="Bidet Inoperative" number="62">The bidet is inoperative.  Repair or replacement is necessary.</item>
        <item name="Bidet Old" number="63">The bidet is old.  Replacement may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Laundry Tub Old Concrete" number="64">The older concrete laundry tub appears serviceable; however, it should be monitored for leakage.</item>
        <item name="Laundry Tub Cracked" number="65">The laundry tub is cracked and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Laundry Tub Leak" number="66">The laundry tub leaks.  Repair or replacement should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Laundry Tub Loose" number="67">The laundry tub is loose and should be properly secured.</item>
        <item name="Hose Bib Leaks" number="68">The hose bib is leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Hose Bib Inoperative" number="69">The hose bib is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Hose Bib Shut Off Needed" number="70">An isolating valve should be installed for the hose bib (exterior faucet).</item>
        <item name="Hose Bib Anti-Siphon Needed" number="71">It is recommended that an anti-siphon device be added to the hose bib(s).</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations IV-A" number="72">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate any main, branch, or shut-off valves; operate or inspect sump pumps or waste ejector pumps; inspect any system that has been winterized, shut down, or otherwise secured; circulating pumps, free-standing appliances, solar water heating systems, water conditioning equipment, filter systems, water mians, private water supply systems, water wells, pressure tanks, sprinkler systems, swimming pools, or fire sprinkler systems; the inaccessible gas supply system for leaks; for sewer clean-outs; or for the presence or operation of private sewage disposal systems; determine quality, potability, or volume of the water supply; or effectiveness of back flow or anti-siphon devices; or verify the functionality of clothes washing drains or floor drains.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="DRAIN/WASTE/VENT COMMENTS" number="422">
        <item name="Marginal Workmanship" number="1">The installation of the waste piping is not workmanlike and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Pipe Leak" number="2">The waste piping is leaking and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Obstruction" number="3">It is suspected that the waste piping is obstructed.  Further investigation and/or repair is needed.</item>
        <item name="Trap Leak" number="4">The trap is leaking and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Trap Suspect" number="5">The trap is in suspect condition.  This area should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="S Trap" number="6">An "S" trap has been used.  Ideally, S traps should be replaced as they are subject to siphoning problems.  S traps are common in older homes.  Replacement is sometimes difficult and thus the S traps are usually tolerated.  Care should be taken to keep the trap "primed".  Fixtures should be monitored for sewer odor.</item>
        <item name="Insufficient Slope" number="7">The waste piping does not have sufficient slope for proper drainage.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Support Insufficient" number="8">The waste piping should be better supported.</item>
        <item name="ABS Pipe Suspect" number="9">The ABS black plastic waste piping may be a defective product.  Connections should be monitored for leakage.  Repair or replacement may become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Connection Suspect" number="10">The waste piping connection is suspect. Repair or replacement may become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Older Piping" number="11">For the most part, the waste piping is older.  It may be prone to unexpected problems.  Improvement is recommended on an as needed basis.</item>
        <item name="Lead Pipe" number="12">The lead waste piping is older and prone to leakage at the connections.</item>
        <item name="Main Clean Out Not Found" number="13">No clean out for the main drain was found.  Clean outs are useful when attempting to remove obstructions within the drainage piping.  It may be prudent to have a clean out installed now, or verify its location with the existing owner.</item>
        <item name="Odor" number="14">A sewer odor was detected.  This usually suggests that the fixture is not properly vented, or that the trap has dried out.  This area should be monitored.  If odor persists, a plumber should be engaged.</item>
        <item name="Openings" number="15">Unsealed opening in the waste piping should be corrected.</item>
        <item name="Venting Suspect" number="16">The presence of sufficient venting for the waste piping is suspect. This should be investigated further and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Stack Height/Size Insufficient" number="17">The vent stack that penetrates the roof should extend at least 6 inches above the roof and should be at least 2 inches in diameter.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations IV-B" number="18">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate any main, branch, or shut-off valves; operate or inspect sump pumps or waste ejector pumps; inspect any system that has been winterized, shut down, or otherwise secured; circulating pumps, free-standing appliances, solar water heating systems, water conditioning equipment, filter systems, water mians, private water supply systems, water wells, pressure tanks, sprinkler systems, swimming pools, or fire sprinkler systems; the inaccessible gas supply system for leaks; for sewer clean-outs; or for the presence or operation of private sewage disposal systems; determine quality, potability, or volume of the water supply; or effectiveness of back flow or anti-siphon devices; or verify the functionality of clothes washing drains or floor drains.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="WATER HEATING COMMENTS" number="423">
        <item name="Old Unit" number="1">The water heater is an older unit that may be approaching the end of its useful life.  It would be wise to budget for a new unit.  One cannot predict with certainty when replacement will become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Unit Middle Aged" number="2">Water heaters have a typical life expectancy of 7 to 12 years.  The existing unit is approaching this age range.  One cannot predict with certainty when replacement will become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Leakage Evidence" number="3">The water heater shows evidence of prior leakage.  This should be carefully monitored and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Needs Service" number="4">It is recommended that the water heater be serviced.</item>
        <item name="Corrosion At Supply Connections" number="5">The supply piping shows evidence of corrosion where it meets the water heater.  This is a common condition and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Reversed Hot And Cold" number="6">The hot and cold supply water connections are reversed at the water heater.  For improved operation, this condition should be corrected.</item>
        <item name="No Shut Off Valve" number="7">There is no shut off valve on the cold water supply to the water heater.  It is suggested that one be installed.</item>
        <item name="No TPR Valve" number="8">For safety reasons, it is recommended that a Temperature and Pressure Relief (TPR) Valve be installed for the water heater.  The lack of such a valve is a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Leaky TPR Valve" number="9">The Temperature and Pressure Relief (TPR) Valve serving the water heater is leaking slightly.  Minor repairs or cleaning can usually rectify this condition.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative TPR Valve" number="10">The Temperature and Pressure Relief (TPR) Valve serving the water heater is inoperative.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Discharge Tube Needs Improve." number="11">The discharge piping serving the Temperature and Pressure Relief (TPR) Valve for the water heater should terminate not less than 6 inches or more than 24 inches above the floor.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="No Safety Pan" number="12">No safety pan and drain was found for the water heater.  This should be repaired by the installation of a pan with a drain by a qualified professional</item>
        <item name="Wiring Needs Conduit" number="13">Wiring serving the electric water heater should be protected by a conduit.</item>
        <item name="Wiring Improvement" number="14">The electrical wiring connected to the water heater is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Missing Cover" number="15">The cover is missing from the water heater burner chamber.  This should be replaced for reasons of safety and efficient combustion.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Cover" number="16">The cover is damaged for the water heater burner chamber.  This should be replaced for reasons of safety and efficient combustion.</item>
        <item name="Missing Controls" number="17">Controls for the water heater are missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Controls" number="18">Controls for the water heater are damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Casing Damage" number="19">The exterior casing of the water heater is damaged.  This should be repaired in the interest of safety and to prevent possible leaking.</item>
        <item name="Burner Dirty" number="20">The water heater burner is dirty.  It should be cleaned and adjusted.</item>
        <item name="Spillage Of Exhaust" number="21">The water heater venting system shows evidence of exhaust "spillage".  This is a serious condition that could be a health threat to the occupants of the home.  This condition should be addressed promptly.</item>
        <item name="Combustion Air" number="22">It is suspected that there is an insufficient supply of combustion air for the water heater.  Improvement is usually straightforward, and should be considered high priority for safety reasons.</item>
        <item name="Draft Diverter Improvement" number="23">The "draft diverter" of the water heater venting system is configured in such a way that it could allow spillage of exhaust products.  This is a potential safety concern that should be addressed promptly.</item>
        <item name="Vent Pipe Aluminum" number="24">The vent pipe serving the water heater appears to be made of aluminum.  This material is not well suited to this application and, for safety reasons, it should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Vent Pipe Clearance" number="25">The vent pipe serving the water heater does not have safe clearance from combustible materials.  This condition should be improved for safety reasons.</item>
        <item name="Vent Pipe Connections" number="26">For enhanced safety, it is recommended that the connections of the water heater venting system be improved.</item>
        <item name="WH Gas Line Material" number="27">Inappropriate material is being used for the water heater gas line.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="WH Gas Valve Location" number="28">A valve for the water heater gas line is in an inappropriate location.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="WH No Gas Shut-Off" number="29">No shut-off for the water heater gas line was found.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Water Heater Gas Leak" number="30">A leak was detected in the water heater gas line.  This should be repaired immediately as it poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Protection From Damage" number="31">Given the location of the water heater, it should be better protected from physical damage.</item>
        <item name="Garage Clearances Need Improve." number="32">Water heaters in garages should be on a raised platform so that the pilots, burner or heating elements are not closer than 18 inches from the garage floor.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Unsafe Location" number="33">The location of the water heater is considered unsafe.  This situation should be remedied for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Improve Mount" number="34">The stand under the water heater does not appear to adequately support the tank safely.  Rebuilding or modifying is recommended.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations IV-C" number="35">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to verify the effectiveness of the temperature and pressure relief valve, discharge piping, or pan drain pipes; operate the temperature and pressure relief valve if the operation of the valve may, in the inspector’s reasonable judgment, cause damage to persons or property; or determine the efficiency or adequacy of the unit.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="HYDRO-THERAPY EQUIPMENT COMMENTS" number="424">
        <item name="Whirlpool Inoperative" number="1">The whirlpool bath was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  This should be investigated further and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Whirlpool Switch Location" number="2">The location of the controls for the whirlpool bath was inappropriate. This should be repaired as is poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Whirlpool Leaks" number="3">The whirlpool bath was found to be leaking at the time of the inspection.  This condition should be repaired to prevent possible structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Leaks Under Whirlpool" number="4">The whirlpool bath was found to be leaking under the tub at the time of the inspection.  This condition should be repaired to prevent possible structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Whirlpool Noisy" number="5">The whirlpool bath was unusually noisy at the time of the inspection.  This should be further investigated.</item>
        <item name="Whirlpool Motor Access" number="6">Access to the whirlpool motor should be provided (or its whereabouts should be verified with the current owner).</item>
        <item name="Whirlpool Cover Missing" number="7">The cover for the whirlpool bath pump was missing and should be replaced (or its whereabouts should be verified with the current owner).</item>
        <item name="Whirlpool Cover Damaged" number="8">The cover for the whirlpool bath pump was damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Whirlpool Lacks GFCI" number="9">A ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) should be installed on the circuit for the whirlpool bath.  A ground fault circuit interrupter offers protection from shock or electrocution.  This should be repaired as is poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Whirlpool GFCI Inoperative" number="10">A ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) installed on the circuit for the whirlpool bath was not operating.  A ground fault circuit interrupter offers protection from shock or electrocution.  This should be repaired as is poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Valves In Poor Condition" number="11">The valves for the whirlpool bath pump and distribution system were found to be in poor condition and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Pipes In Poor Condition" number="12">The piping for the whirlpool bath pump and distribution system were found to be in poor condition and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Grates Damaged" number="13">The grate(s) for the whirlpool bath were found to be damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations IV-B" number="14">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate any main, branch, or shut-off valves; operate or inspect sump pumps or waste ejector pumps; inspect any system that has been winterized, shut down, or otherwise secured; circulating pumps, free-standing appliances, solar water heating systems, water conditioning equipment, filter systems, water mians, private water supply systems, water wells, pressure tanks, sprinkler systems, swimming pools, or fire sprinkler systems; the inaccessible gas supply system for leaks; for sewer clean-outs; or for the presence or operation of private sewage disposal systems; determine quality, potability, or volume of the water supply; or effectiveness of back flow or anti-siphon devices; or verify the functionality of clothes washing drains or floor drains.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations IV-D" number="15">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to determine the adequacy of self-draining features of circulation systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="DISHWASHER COMMENTS" number="425">
        <item name="Dishwasher Old" number="1">The dishwasher is an older unit.  While replacement is not needed right away, it would be wise to budget for a new dishwasher .  In the interim, a higher level of maintenance can be expected.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Inoperative" number="2">The dishwasher is inoperative and should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Noisy" number="3">The dishwasher is excessively noisy and may be in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Rust" number="4">Rust was noted within the dishwasher.  This condition should repaired.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Leaking" number="5">The dishwasher was found to be leaking.  This item should be repaired to prevent possible structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Prior Leakage" number="6">There is evidence of prior leakage in the vicinity of the dishwasher.  This should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Door Seal" number="7">The door seal of the dishwasher should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Door Damage" number="8">The dishwasher door is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Door Spring" number="9">The spring for the dishwasher door is not functioning properly and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Controls Missing" number="10">Controls for the dishwasher were found to be missing.  This condition should repaired.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Controls Damaged" number="11">Controls for the dishwasher were found to be damaged and should repaired.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Spray Arm Problem" number="12">A dishwasher spray arm appears to be defective and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Soap Door Poor" number="13">The dishwasher soap door is in poor condition and may not be functioning as intended.  This item should be repaired</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Trays Poor" number="14">The dish trays for the dishwasher were found to be in poor condition and should repaired.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Drying Elements" number="15">The drying elements for the dishwasher were found to be in poor condition and should repaired.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Latch Damage" number="16">The dishwasher latch is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Drains Improperly" number="17">The dishwasher did not drain properly upon testing.  This should be investigated and repairs undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Drain Connection Marginal" number="18">The dishwasher drain connection at the waste piping is considered marginal. This should be investigated and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Supply Line Connection Marginal" number="19">The dishwasher connection at the supply piping is considered marginal. This should be investigated and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Maintenance Lacking" number="20">The dishwasher appears to have been lacking maintenance.</item>
        <item name="Dishwasher Poorly Attached" number="21">The dishwasher should be better secured.</item>
        <item name="Airgap Device Missing" number="22">The dishwasher lacks an airgap device.  Air gaps are now standard equipment to assure a separation between supply and waste water.  It is advised that one be installed.</item>
        <item name="Airgap Improper" number="23">The dishwasher airgap device does not appear to be properly configured.  Air gaps are now standard equipment to assure a separation between supply and waste water.  It is advised that this condition be investigated and repairs undertaken.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="24">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="FOOD WASTE DISPOSER COMMENTS" number="426">
        <item name="Disposer Old" number="1">The food waste disposer is an older unit.  While replacement is not needed right away, it would be wise to budget for a new food waste disposer.  In the interim, a higher level of maintenance can be expected.</item>
        <item name="Disposer Inoperative" number="2">The food waste disposer is inoperative and should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Disposer Noisy" number="3">The food waste disposer is excessively noisy.  Repairs may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Disposer Seized" number="4">The food waste disposer has seized and should be repaired.  The unit attempts to respond when the power is switched on but does not begin to operate and trips the breaker.</item>
        <item name="Disposer Damaged" number="5">The exterior of the food waste disposer is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Disposer Poorly Secured" number="6">The food waste disposer should be better secured.</item>
        <item name="Disposer Prior Leakage" number="7">There is evidence of prior leakage in the vicinity of the food waste disposer.  This should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Disposer Splash Guard Damaged" number="8">The splash guard for the food waste disposer is damaged and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Disposer Wiring Defective" number="9">The wiring leading to the food waste disposer appears to be defective.  This should be repaired as soon as possible.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="10">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="RANGE HOOD COMMENTS" number="427">
        <item name="Range Hood Fan Inoperative" number="1">The range hood fan is inoperative and should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Range Hood Noisy" number="2">The range hood fan is noisy and may be in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Range Hood Vibration" number="3">The range hood exhibits excessive vibration when run.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Range Hood Speeds" number="4">The range hood does not operate at all speeds.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Range Hood Light Inoperative" number="5">The range hood light is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Range Hood Cleaning Needed" number="6">The range hood requires cleaning.</item>
        <item name="Hood Vent Pipe Damaged" number="7">The vent piping for the range hood is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Hood Vent To Exterior Needed" number="8">The range hood fan should be repaired so as to discharge to the building exterior.</item>
        <item name="Hood Vent Material Improper" number="9">The material used for the range hood venting is improper.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Range Hood Needed" number="10">A range hood is needed for the proper venting of the cooking area.  An appropriately sized unit should be installed.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="11">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="RANGE/OVEN/COOKTOP COMMENTS" number="428">
        <item name="ER - Old" number="1">The electric range is an older unit.  While replacement is not needed right away, it would be wise to budget for a new range.  In the interim, a higher level of maintenance can be expected.</item>
        <item name="ER - Burner Inoperative" number="2">A burner on the electric range is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="ER - Burner Damaged" number="3">A burner on the electric range is damaged and is need of repair.</item>
        <item name="ER - Element Inoperative" number="4">An element in the oven of the electric range is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="ER - Element Damaged" number="5">An element in the oven of the electric range is damaged and is need of repair.</item>
        <item name="ER - Knob Damaged" number="6">A control knob on the electric range is damaged and is need of repair.</item>
        <item name="ER - Oven Door Damaged" number="7">The oven door of the electric range is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="ER - Oven Door Springs" number="8">The springs for the oven door of the range require improvement.</item>
        <item name="ER - Oven Door Latch" number="9">The door latch for the electric range was not working properly and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="ER - Oven Door Gasket" number="10">The door gasket for the electric range was in poor condition and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="ER - Oven Door Seal" number="11">The door for the electric range did seal adequately and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="ER - Drawer Damaged" number="12">The utility drawer in the range is damaged and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="ER - Maintenance Lacking" number="13">The electric range has been lacking maintenance somewhat.</item>
        <item name="ER - Oven Light Inoperative" number="14">The oven light in the range is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="ER - Clock Inoperative" number="15">The clock for the electric range was inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="ER - Thermostat" number="16">The thermostat for the electric range was found to be inaccurate and should be repaired.  The temperature was found to be greater than a 25 degree difference of 350 degrees as measured by a detached thermometer.</item>
        <item name="GR - Old" number="17">The gas range is an older unit.  While replacement is not needed right away, it would be wise to budget for a new range.  In the interim, a higher level of maintenance can be expected.</item>
        <item name="GR - Burner Inoperative" number="18">A burner on the gas range is inoperative and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="GR - Burner Servicing Needed" number="19">The burners on the gas range need servicing.</item>
        <item name="GR - Pilot Suspect" number="20">The pilot light for the gas range is in suspect condition.</item>
        <item name="GR - Knob Damaged" number="21">A control knob on the gas range is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="GR - Oven Door Damaged" number="22">The oven door of the gas range is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="GR - Oven Door Springs" number="23">The springs for the oven door of the range require improvement.</item>
        <item name="GR - Oven Door Latch" number="24">The door latch for the gas range was not working properly and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="GR - Oven Door Gasket" number="25">The door gasket for the gas range was in poor condition and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="GR - Oven Door Seal" number="26">The door for the gas range did seal adequately and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="GR - Drawer Damaged" number="27">The utility drawer in the gas range is damaged and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="GR - Maintenance Lacking" number="28">The gas range has been lacking maintenance somewhat.</item>
        <item name="GR - Oven Light Inoperative" number="29">The oven light in the range is inoperative and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="GR - Timer Inoperative" number="30">The timer for the oven was found to be inoperative when tested.  This item should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="GR - Clock Inoperative" number="31">The clock for the gas range was inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="GR - Thermostat" number="32">The thermostat for the gas range was found to be inaccurate and should be repaired.  The temperature was found to be greater than a 25 degree difference of 350 degrees as measured by a detached thermometer.</item>
        <item name="GR - Gas Connection Unsafe" number="33">The gas line connection at the gas range is not considered safe.  This situation should be investigated immediately for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="GR - No Shut Off In Room" number="34">There does not appear to be a gas shut off in the kitchen.  This situation should be investigated immediately for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="GR - Gas Leak" number="35">There is evidence of a gas leak in the vicinity of the gas range.  This is a serious safety concern.  It is recommended that the gas utility be engaged immediately.  The current occupants of the home should be notified.</item>
        <item name="Oven Old" number="36">The oven is an older unit.  While replacement is not needed right away, it would be wise to budget for a new oven.  In the interim, a higher level of maintenance can be expected.</item>
        <item name="Oven Element Inoperative" number="37">An element in the oven is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Element Damaged" number="38">An element in the oven is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Knob Damaged" number="39">A control knob for the oven is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Door Damaged" number="40">The oven door is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Door Springs" number="41">The springs for the oven door require improvement.</item>
        <item name="Oven Door Latch" number="42">The door latch for the oven was not working properly and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Door Gasket" number="43">The door gasket for the oven was in poor condition and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Door Seal" number="44">The door for the oven did seal adequately and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Maintenance Lacking" number="45">The oven has been lacking maintenance somewhat.</item>
        <item name="Oven Light Inoperative" number="46">The oven light is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Timer Inoperative" number="47">The timer for the oven was inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Clock Inoperative" number="48">The clock for the oven was inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Oven Thermostat" number="49">The thermostat for the oven was found to be inaccurate and should be repaired.  The temperature was found to be greater than a 25 degree difference of 350 degrees as measured by a detached thermometer.</item>
        <item name="Oven Mounting" number="50">The oven was not securely fastened to the cabinet.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="EC - Old" number="51">The electric cooktop is an older unit.  While replacement is not needed right away, it would be wise to budget for a new cooktop.  In the interim, a higher level of maintenance can be expected.</item>
        <item name="EC - Burner Inoperative" number="52">A burner on the electric cooktop is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="EC - Burner Damaged" number="53">A burner on the electric cooktop is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="EC - Knob Damaged" number="54">A control knob on the electric cooktop is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="EC - Maintenance Lacking" number="55">The electric cooktop has been lacking maintenance somewhat.</item>
        <item name="EC - Wiring Defective" number="56">The wiring leading to the electric cooktop appears to be defective.  This should be repaired as soon as possible.</item>
        <item name="GC - Old" number="57">The gas cooktop is an older unit.  While replacement is not needed right away, it would be wise to budget for a new cooktop.  In the interim, a higher level of maintenance can be expected.</item>
        <item name="GC - Burner Inoperative" number="58">A burner on the gas cooktop is inoperative and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="GC - Burner Servicing Needed" number="59">The burners on the gas cooktop need servicing.</item>
        <item name="GC - Pilot Suspect" number="60">The pilot light for the gas cooktop is in suspect condition.  Repairs should be undertaken as necessary.</item>
        <item name="GC - Knob Damaged" number="61">A control knob on the gas cooktop is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="GC - Gas Connection Unsafe" number="62">The gas line connection at the gas cooktop is not considered safe.  This situation should be investigated immediately for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="GC - No Shut Off In Room" number="63">There does not appear to be a gas shut off in the kitchen.  This situation should be investigated immediately for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="GC - Gas Leak" number="64">There is evidence of a gas leak in the vicinity of the gas cooktop.  This is a serious safety concern.  It is recommended that the gas utility be engaged immediately.  The current occupants of the home should be notified.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="65">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="MICROWAVE COMMENTS" number="429">
        <item name="Microwave Old" number="1">The microwave oven is an older unit.  While replacement is not needed right away, it would be wise to budget for a new microwave oven.  In the interim, a higher level of maintenance can be expected.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Inoperative" number="2">The microwave oven was inoperative on the day of the inspection.  This should be investigated further and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Does Not Heat" number="3">Components of the microwave operated but did not heat when tested.  This microwave should be repaired and/or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Controls Damaged" number="4">The controls for the microwave oven are damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Knob Damaged" number="5">A control knob for the microwave oven is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Door Damaged" number="6">The microwave oven door is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Door Springs" number="7">The springs for the microwave oven door require improvement.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Door Seal" number="8">The microwave door did not seal properly.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Maintenance Lacking" number="9">The microwave oven has been lacking maintenance somewhat.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Light Inoperative" number="10">The microwave oven light is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Microwave Mounting" number="11">The microwave was not securely mounted.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="12">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="TRASH COMPACTOR COMMENTS" number="430">
        <item name="Compactor Old" number="1">The trash compactor is an older unit.  While replacement is not needed right away, it would be wise to budget for a new trash compactor.  In the interim, a higher level of maintenance can be expected.</item>
        <item name="Compactor Inoperative" number="2">The trash compactor is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Compactor Noisy" number="3">The trash compactor is excessively noisy and may be in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Compactor Vibration" number="4">The compactor exhibits excessive vibration when run.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Compactor Mounting" number="5">The compactor was not securely mounted to the surrounding cabinets.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Compactor Corrosion" number="6">The trash compactor shows evidence of corrosion.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Compactor Door Damage" number="7">The trash compactor door is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Compactor Unsanitary" number="8">The trash compactor is considered unsanitary.  Cleaning and servicing are recommended.</item>
        <item name="Compactor Wiring Defective" number="9">The wiring leading to the trash compactor appears to be defective.  This should be repaired as soon as possible.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="10">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="EXHAUST FAN/HEATER COMMENTS" number="431">
        <item name="Exhaust Fan Inoperative" number="1">The exhaust fan is inoperative and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Exhaust Fan Noisy" number="2">The exhaust fan is noisy and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Exhaust Fan Vibration" number="3">The bathroom exhaust fan exhibits excessive vibration when run.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Exhaust Fan Light Inoperative" number="4">The exhaust fan light is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Vent To Exterior Needed" number="5">The bathroom exhaust fan should be repaired so as to discharge to the building exterior.</item>
        <item name="Heater Inoperative" number="6">An inoperative bathroom heater was found.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Heater Damaged" number="7">A damaged heater was observed and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Heater Rusted" number="8">Bathroom heater show evidence of corrosion.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Control" number="9">Bathroom heater controls are damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Heaters Old" number="10">The bathroom heaters are older.  Their reliability may be reduced.  Replacement units may be necessary over time.</item>
        <item name="Condensation/Vent Problems" number="11">As with many homes that are electrically heated, there is evidence of condensation and ventilation difficulties.  This condition should be monitored and/or repaired.  If this proves to be a problem, steps should be taken to better control humidity and improve air change within the house.  This could be as simple as installing exhaust fans.  A more sophisticated measure would be to install a heat recovery ventilator.</item>
        <item name="Wiring Unsafe" number="12">Unsafe electric heater wiring was observed.  For safety reasons, this should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="13">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="WHOLE HOUSE VACUUM COMMENTS" number="432">
        <item name="Vacuum Inoperative" number="1">The whole house vacuum system is inoperative.  Further investigation and/or repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Vacuum Noisy" number="2">The whole house vacuum system is excessively noisy and may be in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Vacuum Low Suction" number="3">The suction of the whole house vacuum system is relatively low.  Replacing the filter and checking for obstructions in the piping is recommended.  If this does not remedy the situation, further investigation and/or repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations VI-14" number="4">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to inspect the attachments or hoses; or verify that accessory components are present.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="GARAGE DOOR OPERATOR COMMENTS" number="433">
        <item name="Opener Inoperative" number="1">The garage door opener is inoperative.  It should be repaired as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Opener Damaged" number="2">The garage door opener is damaged.  It should be repaired as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Opener Auto Reverse Defective" number="3">The garage door opener did not automatically reverse under resistance to closing.  There is a serious risk of injury, particularly to children, under this condition.  Improvement may be as simple as adjusting the sensitivity control on the opener.  This should be repaired immediately.</item>
        <item name="Opener Sensor Inoperative" number="4">The electronic sensor for the garage door opener did not automatically reverse the closing of the garage door when tested.  There is a serious risk of injury, particularly to children, under this condition. This should be repaired immediately.</item>
        <item name="Opener Sensor Height" number="5">The electronic sensor for the garage door opener was found to be installed at an improper height from the garage floor. This should be repaired as it poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="6">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="DOOR BELL/CHIMES COMMENTS" number="434">
        <item name="Door Bell Inoperative" number="1">The door bell was inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Door Bell Damaged" number="2">Components of the door bell were found to be damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="3">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="DRYER VENT COMMENTS" number="435">
        <item name="Vent Dryer To Exterior" number="1">The clothes dryer should be vented to the building exterior.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Vent Pipe Poor" number="2">The clothes dryer exhaust vent pipe was found to be in poor condition and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="3">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="GARAGE DOOR OPERATOR COMMENTS" number="437">
        <item name="Opener Inoperative" number="1">The garage door opener is inoperative.  It should be repaired as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Opener Damaged" number="2">The garage door opener is damaged.  It should be repaired as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Opener Auto Reverse Defective" number="3">The garage door opener did not automatically reverse under resistance to closing.  There is a serious risk of injury, particularly to children, under this condition.  Improvement may be as simple as adjusting the sensitivity control on the opener.  This should be repaired immediately.</item>
        <item name="Opener Sensor Inoperative" number="4">The electronic sensor for the garage door opener did not automatically reverse the closing of the garage door when tested.  There is a serious risk of injury, particularly to children, under this condition. This should be repaired immediately.</item>
        <item name="Opener Sensor Height" number="5">The electronic sensor for the garage door opener was found to be installed at an improper height from the garage floor. This should be repaired as it poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations V" number="6">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to operate or determine the condition of other auxiliary components of inspected items; test for microwave oven radiation leaks; inspect self-cleaning functions; test trash compactor ram pressure; or determine the adequacy of venting systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="LAWN SPRINKLERS COMMENTS" number="438">
        <item name="Valves Leaking" number="1">The sprinkler system valves were observed to be leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Low Water Pressure" number="2">The water pressure from the sprinkler heads was insufficient to provide full coverage.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Re-Direct Spray" number="3">The water spray from the sprinkler system should be re-directed away from the structure and/or any fencing, decks, etc., to decrease the possibility of damage.</item>
        <item name="Bury Exposed Lines" number="4">It is recommended that exposed water lines for the sprinkler system be buried to lessen the potential of damage.</item>
        <item name="Missing Sprinkler Heads" number="5">Missing sprinkler heads were noted.  This condition should be remedied to ensure adequate spray coverage for the entire sprinkler system.</item>
        <item name="Broken Sprinkler Heads" number="6">Broken sprinkler heads were noted.  This condition should be remedied to ensure adequate spray coverage for the entire sprinkler system.</item>
        <item name="Anti-Siphon Valves Recommended" number="7">Anti-siphon valves are recommended for the sprinkler system.</item>
        <item name="Partially Buried Valves" number="8">Partially buried valves were noted for the sprinkler system.  This condition should be remedied to provide adequate access.</item>
        <item name="Spray Coverage Not Verified" number="9">Spray coverage for the sprinkler system was not verified as part of this inspection.  Coverage should be monitored for the system and adjusted accordingly to ensure even watering of the landscaping.</item>
        <item name="All Zones Not Operating" number="10">Not all of the zones for the sprinkler system were operating at the time of the inspection.  This condition should be investigated and repaired.</item>
        <item name="Control Box Improper Wiring" number="11">The wiring for the sprinkler system control box is improper and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Control Box Damaged Wiring" number="12">The wiring for the sprinkler system control box is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Control Box Mounting" number="13">The control box for the sprinkler system is not mounted securely and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations VI-A" number="14">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to inspect for effective coverage of the sprinker system; the automatic function of the timer or control box; the effectiveness of the rain or freeze sensor; or sizing and effectiveness of anti-siphon devices or backflow preventers.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="SWIMMING POOL/EQUIPMENT" number="439">
        <item name="Construction: In Ground" number="1">Construction type: In-ground</item>
        <item name="Construction: Above Ground" number="2">Construction type: Above-ground</item>
        <item name="Inoperative" number="3">This component was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  Further investigation and/or repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Defective" number="4">This component was defective at the time of the inspection.  Repair or replacement should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Leaking" number="5">This component was observed to be leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Damaged" number="6">This component was observed to be damaged and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Older" number="7">This component is older.  It may require a slightly higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.</item>
        <item name="Obsolete" number="8">This component is obsolete and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Unsafe" number="9">This component is considered to be unsafe.  For safety reasons, it should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="Missing" number="10">This component was missing at the time of the inspection.  It should be provided to ensure proper function.</item>
        <item name="Not Grounded" number="11">This component was not grounded properly and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Improper Wiring" number="12">This component was observed to be improperly wired and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Maintenance Lacking" number="13">This component has been lacking maintenance somewhat.  A qualified technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Pool - Gas Line Material" number="14">Inappropriate material is being used for the gas lines.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Pool - Gas Valve Location" number="15">A valve for the gas line is in an inappropriate location.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Pool - No Gas Shut-Off" number="16">No shut-off for the gas line was found.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Gas Leak" number="17">A gas leak was detected.  This is a serious safety concern.  It is recommended that the gas utility be engaged immediately.  The current occupants of the home should be notified.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations VI-B" number="18">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to dismantle or otherwise open any components or lines; operate valves; uncover or excavate any lines or concealed components of the system or determine the presence of sub-surface leaks; fill the pool, spa, or hot tub with water; inspect any system that has been winterized, shut down, or otherwise secured; determine the presence of sub-surface water tables; or inspect ancillary equipment such as computer controls, covers, chlorinators or other chemical dispensers, or water ionization devices or conditioners other than required by this section.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="OUTBUILDINGS COMMENTS" number="440">
        <item name="Cracks Minor/Settling" number="1">Common minor cracks were observed in the foundation walls of the house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses. New Item Need to be redefined</item>
        <item name="Cracks Minor/Shrinkage" number="2">Minor vertical cracking was observed in the foundation.  This type of cracking is usually the result of shrinkage of the concrete as it cures.  Shrinkage cracks are very common and should not be cause for alarm.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Moderate/Settling" number="3">Slightly greater than typical foundation cracking was observed.  The amount of movement does not suggest a serious structural problem.  This area should, of course, be monitored.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Major/Settling" number="4">Substantial foundation cracking was observed.  This implies that structural movement of the building has occurred.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.  A structural engineer should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Spalling (Exterior)" number="5">Surface deterioration (known as spalling) was observed on the exterior of the exposed foundation walls.  This condition is common in many homes and does not usually represent a structural concern.  In an effort to prevent long term deterioration, it would be wise to consider parging deteriorated areas.  Lot drainage improvements, as outlined in the "Exterior" section of this report are also recommended.</item>
        <item name="Mortar Deterioration (Exterior)" number="6">Foundation wall mortar joints show evidence of deterioration.  It would be wise to consider repointing deteriorated areas in order to improve durability.</item>
        <item name="Backfill Height Excessive" number="7">The height of the backfill (soil adjacent to the foundation) appears to exceed the acceptable limit.  This could result in excessive force on the foundation.  A structural engineer or qualified contractor should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Exterior Wall Cracks" number="8">Cracks were observed on the exterior walls of the house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Interior Wall Cracks" number="9">Cracks were observed on the interior walls of the house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Door Frames" number="10">Door frames were found to be out-of-square within house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Floor Slope" number="11">Sloping floors were observed within house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Minor Repairs Only" number="12">Minor repairs to the roofing are recommended.  Damaged or missing roofing material should be repaired.  All roof penetrations should be examined and sealed as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Replacement Needed" number="13">The roofing was found to be in poor condition and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Nearing End Of Life Cycle" number="14">The roofing is nearing the end of its life cycle.  Replacement will become necessary in the near future.</item>
        <item name="Near End Of Life Cycle - Minor" number="15">The roofing is nearing the end of its life cycle.  Minor repairs are recommended in the short term to maintain the weather tightness of the roof.  Damaged or missing roofing material should be repaired.  All roof penetrations should be examined and sealed as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition" number="16">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.</item>
        <item name="Fair Cond. - Amateur Install" number="17">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  The installation of this roofing appears to have been performed in an amateur fashion.  While this condition does not pose a serious short term concern, it may effect the reliability and/or longevity of the roof.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition - Uneven Wear" number="18">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  This roofing is wearing at uneven rates.  The sides of the roof that are most exposed to the sun’s light are wearing more quickly than the more shaded areas.  Repair or replacement of deteriorated roofing may be needed in some areas, prior to the entire roof covering requiring replacement.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition - Premature Flaws" number="19">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  The roofing shows evidence of flaws that are premature for roofing of this age.  This may be a manufacturing defect.  This condition may influence the life expectancy of the roofing.  The manufacturer of installer could be consulted for further evaluation.</item>
        <item name="Good Cond. - Amateur Install" number="20">The roofing is considered to be in good condition.  The installation of this roofing appears to have been performed in an amateur fashion.  While this does not pose a serious short term concern, it may have a longer term affect on the reliability and/or longevity of the roof.</item>
        <item name="Good Condition - Uneven Wear" number="21">The roofing is considered to be in good condition.  This roofing is wearing at uneven rates.  The sides of the roof that are most exposed to the sun’s light are wearing more quickly than the more shaded areas.  Repair or replacement of deteriorated roofing may be needed in some areas, prior to the entire roof covering requiring replacement.</item>
        <item name="Inappropriate Mat. - Low Slope" number="22">The roofing is not intended for this low slope application.  While this condition does not pose a serious short term concern, it may affect the reliability and longevity of this section of roof.</item>
        <item name="Older Roofs - Maintenance Notes" number="23">Older roofs are, by their nature, a high maintenance roof.  Annual inspection and repair should be anticipated.  In addition, the older flashings should be monitored.  In some cases, a deteriorated flashing can result in expensive repairs, because sections of the roofing have to be removed.  As a rule of thumb, replacement of the entire roof covering may be logical if more than ten percent of the roof requires repair.</item>
        <item name="Vulnerable Areas" number="24">The design of the roofing system is such that several vulnerable areas exist.  There is a higher potential for unanticipated repairs.  Annual inspections and ongoing maintenance will be critical to the performance of the roofing system.</item>
        <item name="Prior Repairs Evident" number="25">Prior repairs to the roofing are evident.  This would suggest that problems have been experienced in the past.  This area should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Remove Debris" number="26">Debris should be removed from the roofing.</item>
        <item name="Exposed Felt/Sheathing" number="27">Exposed sheathing is visible where the roofing is damaged.  Damaged or missing roofing material should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Strip When Re-Roofing" number="28">It is recommended that roofing materials be removed prior to re-roofing.</item>
        <item name="Replacement Needed" number="29">The roofing was found to be in poor condition and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Nearing End Of Life Cycle" number="30">The roofing is nearing the end of its life cycle.  Replacement will become necessary in the near future.</item>
        <item name="Near End Of Life - Flaws" number="31">The roofing is nearing the end of its life cycle.  The membrane exhibits flaws (such as blistering, cracking, etc.) that are symptomatic of an older flat roof.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition" number="32">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.</item>
        <item name="Fair Cond. - Material/Install" number="33">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  The installation of this roofing appears to have been performed in an amateur fashion.  This roofing material is not ideally suited to a flat roof application.  While this condition does not pose a serious short term concern, it may affect the reliability and/or longevity of the roof.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition - Lack Of Gravel" number="34">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  The lack of gravel on the membrane has led to a shortened life expectancy.  Applying gravel over the membrane may help to prolong the life of this roof.</item>
        <item name="Fair Condition - Water Ponding" number="35">The roofing is considered to be in fair condition.  Water appears to pond on the membrane.  This usually leads to a shortened life expectancy and increases the potential for damage if leakage occurs.  Improvement is not usually practical until re-roofing is performed.  At that time, the roof should be appropriately sloped, or drains should be provided as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Amateur Install - Good Cond." number="36">The roofing is considered to be in reasonably good condition.  The installation of this roofing appears to have been performed in an amateur fashion.  This roofing material is not ideally suited to a flat roof application.  While this condition does not pose a serious short term concern, it may affect the reliability and/or longevity of the roof.</item>
        <item name="Drains Congested" number="37">The congested roof drains should be cleared and maintained free of debris.</item>
        <item name="UV Protect. Needed - Single Ply" number="38">Ideally, some form of ultraviolet protection would be provided for the membrane.  This protection typically comes in the form of paint, foil or gravel.</item>
        <item name="Incompatible Materials" number="39">The membrane may not be compatible to the adjoining asphalt roofing.  A qualified licensed roofer should be consulted.</item>
        <item name="Voids In Gravel" number="40">Voids in the gravel were observed on the roofing.  This usually leads to a shortened life expectancy and increases the potential for ultraviolet damage to the roofing.  Missing gravel should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Seam Failure" number="41">The roofing shows evidence of seam failure (the seams of the membrane coming apart).  Repairs are recommended.</item>
        <item name="Typical Maintenance Needed" number="42">The roofing requires maintenance.  Moss should be cleared from the roof, voids in the gravel should be improved, and any blisters should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Prior Repairs Evident" number="43">Prior repairs to the roofing are evident.  This would suggest that problems have been experienced in the past.  This area should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Strip When Re-Roofing" number="44">It is recommended that roofing materials be removed prior to re-roofing.</item>
        <item name="Old - Replacement Needed" number="45">The flashing is old and should be replaced to avoid leaks.</item>
        <item name="Leak - Replacement Needed" number="46">The flashing leaks and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Leak - Patching Needed" number="47">The flashing leaks and should be patched. If this is unsuccessful, replacement will be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Vulnerable - Prior Leak" number="48">The flashing is vulnerable, has leaked in the past, and should be watched carefully for leaks.</item>
        <item name="Holes - Temporary Patching" number="49">Holes were observed in the flashing. If patching is unsuccessful, replacement will be necessary to stop leaks.</item>
        <item name="Holes - Replacement Needed" number="50">Holes were observed in the flashing. It should be replaced to stop leaks.</item>
        <item name="Rust" number="51">The flashing is rusting. It should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Loose" number="52">The flashing is loose and should be re-secured to avoid leaks.</item>
        <item name="Incomplete Installation" number="53">The installation of the flashing is incomplete and should be repaired to avoid leaks.</item>
        <item name="Nail Heads Exposed" number="54">Nail heads are exposed at the flashing. They should be sealed to reduce risk of leaks.</item>
        <item name="Lack Of Clearance - Siding/Roof" number="55">The clearance of the siding at the flashing is insufficient. This condition leaves the siding vulnerable to rot. This detail is usually repaired when siding needs repair or replacement or when re-roofing work is performed.</item>
        <item name="Skylight - Install Low Quality" number="56">The installation of the skylight is low quality and will be extremely vulnerable to leakage.  Repair is recommended.</item>
        <item name="Skylight Leakage" number="57">The flashing shows evidence of leaks. In some cases, patching the flashing will prevent leaks. If this approach is unsuccessful, re-installing the skylight may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Cracked/Broken" number="58">The skylight is cracked. It should be repaired for safety and to avoid leaks.</item>
        <item name="Cleaning Needed" number="59">The gutters require cleaning to avoid spilling roof runoff around the building – a potential source of water entry or water damage.</item>
        <item name="Leaks Minor" number="60">Minor leaks in the gutters should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Slope Insufficient" number="61">The gutters do not appear to have sufficient slope to drain properly. If they do not perform as intended, the slope should be adjusted to avoid spilling roof runoff around the building – a potential source of water entry or water damage.</item>
        <item name="Gutters Damaged" number="62">Damaged gutters should be repaired or replaced as necessary to avoid spilling roof runoff around the building – a potential source of water entry or water damage.</item>
        <item name="Old Steel - Eventual Replace" number="63">The old galvanized gutters and downspouts are rusting noticeably. Replacement should be anticipated over the next few years. In the interim, leaks that develop should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Old Steel - Replacement" number="64">The old galvanized gutters and downspouts should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Downspouts Insufficient Number" number="65">There does not appear to be a sufficient number of downspouts. If practical, additional downspouts should be installed to avoid spilling roof runoff around the building – a potential source of water entry or water damage.</item>
        <item name="Downspout Discharge Near House" number="66">The downspout(s) should discharge water at least five (5) feet from the house. Storm water should be encouraged to flow away from the building at the point of discharge.</item>
        <item name="Downspouts Clogged Below Grade?" number="67">The downspouts that discharge below grade level should be monitored. If they are ever suspected to be clogged or disconnected below grade, they should be redirected to discharge at least five (5) feet from the building. Foundation leakage adjacent to a downspout is an indication of a problem below grade.</item>
        <item name="Downspout Discharge Onto Roof" number="68">Downspout(s) that discharge onto the roof should be extended to discharge directly into the gutters below. This condition, if left unattended, can result in premature deterioration of the roofing under the end of the downspout.</item>
        <item name="Downspout Loose/Damaged" number="69">Loose or damaged downspouts should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="Ridge Sag" number="70">The ridge of the roof appears to have sagged.  This condition is common in many older homes. Strengthening the roof structure would resist further movement.</item>
        <item name="Rafter Sag" number="71">The rafters of the roof structure show evidence of sagging.  Strengthening the roof structure would resist further movement.</item>
        <item name="Collar Ties Insufficient" number="72">Ideally, collar ties (horizontal members running between each rafter, near their mid-span) should be provided for all rafters.  Collar ties help to resist rafter sag.  Installation is usually very simple.</item>
        <item name="Sheathing Unevenness (Truss)" number="73">Some unevenness in the roof sheathing was observed.  This condition is common where prefabricated roof trusses are used, and spaced two feet apart.  The sheathing sags between the trusses.</item>
        <item name="Truss Uplift" number="74">As evidenced by cracking at the intersection of the interior wall and ceiling, the roof structure appears to suffer from "truss uplift".  This condition is not uncommon in homes employing prefabricated trusses in colder climates.  Truss uplift itself does not represent a serious structural concern.  Cosmetic improvements on the interior of the home, such as the installation of a cove moulding secured to the ceiling, may be desirable to disguise interior cracks.</item>
        <item name="Truss Cut/Altered" number="75">The trusses of the roof structure appear to have been altered.  Cutting or altering the chords of a truss can sacrifice the integrity of the truss.  Special engineering considerations are usually required when trusses are altered.  This area should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="FBM Plywood" number="76">It is suspected that FBM (Fire Retardant Treated) Plywood has been used as roof sheathing.  This type of sheathing is prone to de-lamination and weakening.  This roof sheathing should be carefully monitored.  Sections that begin to fail should be replaced.  During any re-roofing, sheathing improvements would be logical.</item>
        <item name="Sheathing Condensation" number="77">Evidence of condensation (in the form of mildew) was observed on the underside of the roof sheathing.  This condition can weaken the sheathing and ultimately necessitate replacement.  Improved roof and attic ventilation (see Insulation and Ventilation) typically control condensation.  During any planned re-roofing, the sheathing should be investigated to determine if replacement is needed.</item>
        <item name="Sheathing Delaminated" number="78">The roof sheathing is de-laminating (deterioration caused by moisture).  In most cases, damaged roof sheathing must be replaced prior to re-roofing.  Improved roof and attic ventilation (see Insulation and Ventilation) typically control moisture levels within the roof structure.  This condition should be further investigated when re-roofing.</item>
        <item name="Insulation Stains Noted" number="79">Stains on the insulation were observed as evidence of prior roof leakage.</item>
        <item name="Major Leaks Noted" number="80">Substantial evidence of roof leakage was observed.  This condition should be investigated further and repairs made, as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Holes/Light Visible" number="81">While investigating the roof structure, outside light was visible.  This condition suggests that openings exist in the roofing materials.  Repairs should be made, as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Prior Repairs Noted" number="82">Prior repairs to the roof structure are evident.  It may be wise to consult the current owner regarding their knowledge of the roof structure and/or any repairs that became necessary.</item>
        <item name="Improve Insulation" number="83">Insulation improvements may be cost effective, depending on the anticipated term of ownership.</item>
        <item name="Even Out Insulation" number="84">Insulation should be evened out.</item>
        <item name="Compressed Insulation" number="85">Compressed insulation should be rearranged.</item>
        <item name="Skylight Well Insulation Needed" number="86">The skylight well should be better insulated.</item>
        <item name="Improve Ventilation" number="87">The level of ventilation should be improved.  It is generally recommended that one (1) square foot of free vent area be provided for every one hundred and fifty (150) square feet of ceiling area.  Proper ventilation will help to keep the house cooler during warm weather and extend the life of roofing materials.  In colder climates, it will help reduce the potential for ice dams on the roof and condensation within the attic.</item>
        <item name="Marginal Ventilation" number="88">The level of ventilation is considered marginal.  It is generally recommended that one (1) square foot of free vent area be provided for every one hundred and fifty (150) square feet of ceiling area.  Proper ventilation will help to keep the house cooler during warm weather and extend the life of roofing materials.  In colder climates, it will help reduce the potential for ice dams on the roof and condensation within the attic.</item>
        <item name="Soffit Vents Congested?" number="89">The passage of air between the soffit vents and the roof cavity appears to be obstructed.  "Baffles" should be provided to hold back insulation and allow for free movement of air within the roof space.  This area should be further investigated and improved where necessary.</item>
        <item name="Screens On Vents Needed" number="90">Roof vents should be screened to prevent insect and vermin entry.</item>
        <item name="Sloped Ceil. Questionable Vent." number="91">The ventilation of the sloped ceiling is questionable.  Proper ventilation of cathedral roofs is rarely achieved.  As a result, these areas tend to be prone to difficulty, particularly in colder climates.  Ice damming on the roof and condensation within the roof space are common problems.  These areas should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Condensation/Mildew" number="92">Evidence of condensation and mildew was observed.  This condition is usually the result of insufficient ventilation.  Ventilation should be improved and this area should be monitored.  If ignored, this situation could worsen and cause substantial rot.</item>
        <item name="Power Ventilator Inoperative" number="93">The power ventilator appears to be inoperative.  The unit should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Access Hatch Needs Insulation" number="94">Ideally, the attic access hatch should be better insulated.</item>
        <item name="Ducts In Attic Need Insulation" number="95">The ductwork should be better insulated.  This should reduce energy costs.</item>
        <item name="Vent Exhaust Fan To Outside" number="96">Exhaust vent pipes should be insulated and vented to the building exterior.</item>
        <item name="Exhaust Vent Needs Insulation" number="97">Insulation should be provided on exhaust vent pipes.</item>
        <item name="Check Out Recessed Lights" number="98">Recessed lights can pose a fire hazard if not specifically designed for installation in an insulated ceiling.  It is recommended that a licensed electrician be contacted to further evaluate these light fixtures.</item>
        <item name="Vermin Activity Noted" number="99">There is evidence of vermin activity.  A pest control specialist should be consulted in this regard.</item>
        <item name="Water Staining" number="100">Water staining was noted.  The cause for the staining should be determined and repairs undertaken, if necessary, to prevent structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Damage" number="101">ined</item>
        <item name="Patching" number="102">Evidence of patching was detected.</item>
        <item name="Damage Noted" number="103">Damage to the interior finish was observed and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Minor Cracks" number="104">Minor cracks were noted.  This condition is mainly cosmetic in nature and should be patched.</item>
        <item name="Larger Cracks" number="105">Larger than typical cracks were noted. This condition could indicate greater than normal movement within the structure and potential structural problems.  Further investigation may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Drywall Flaws" number="106">Typical drywall flaws were observed. This condition is mainly cosmetic in nature and should be patched.</item>
        <item name="Loose/Weakened" number="107">Loose or weakened finishes were detected.  This should be repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Bulging Plaster" number="108">The plaster shows evidence of bulging.  Repairs may be desirable.</item>
        <item name="Weakness In Plaster" number="109">The plaster finishes show evidence of weakening, as is common in many older homes.  This should be repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Amateur Installation" number="110">The installation of interior finishes is considered to be amateur quality.</item>
        <item name="Poor Workmanship" number="111">Evidence of substandard workmanship was observed.</item>
        <item name="Installation Incomplete" number="112">The installation of interior finishes is incomplete.</item>
        <item name="Mildew" number="113">Signs of mildew were observed. The cause should be investigated and/or repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Staining" number="114">Water staining was noted.  The cause for the staining should be determined and repairs undertaken, if necessary, to prevent structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Damage" number="115">ined</item>
        <item name="Cracks Typical" number="116">Typical minor cracking was observed on the exterior walls of the house.  This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Moderate" number="117">Slightly larger than typical exterior wall cracking was observed.  The amount of movement does not suggest a serious structural problem.  This area should, of course, be monitored.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Major" number="118">Pronounced exterior wall cracks were observed.  This implies that structural movement of the building has occurred.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.  A structural engineer should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Weep Holes Blocked" number="119">Blocked weep holes (openings in the mortar joints, typically found at foundation level) in the brick veneer wall structure should be cleared.</item>
        <item name="Corbelling Excessive" number="120">The overhang of the brick at the foundation wall, also known as corbelling, is excessive.  This could lead to some instability of the brickwork.  If movement occurs, re-supporting the brick would be advisable.</item>
        <item name="Lintel Movement/Cracks" number="121">Exterior wall cracks above a lintel (in effect, a beam supporting the brickwork above an opening in the wall) suggests that the lintel may be marginally adequate.  This condition is not uncommon.</item>
        <item name="Bowing" number="122">Bowing of the exterior wall structure was observed.  This implies that structural movement of the building has occurred.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.  A structural engineer should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Leaning" number="123">The exterior wall structure is leaning.  This implies that structural movement of the building has occurred.  The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.  A structural engineer should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Water Staining" number="124">Water staining was noted.  The cause for the staining should be determined and repairs undertaken, if necessary, to prevent structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Damage" number="125">ined</item>
        <item name="Patching" number="126">Evidence of patching was detected.</item>
        <item name="Damage Noted" number="127">Damage to the interior finish was observed and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Minor Cracks" number="128">Minor cracks were noted.  This condition is mainly cosmetic in nature and should be patched.</item>
        <item name="Larger Cracks" number="129">Larger than typical cracks were noted. This condition could indicate greater than normal movement within the structure and potential structural problems.  Further investigation may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Drywall Flaws" number="130">Typical drywall flaws were observed. This condition is mainly cosmetic in nature and should be patched.</item>
        <item name="Loose/Weakened" number="131">Loose or weakened finishes were detected.  This should be repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Bulging Plaster" number="132">The plaster shows evidence of bulging.  Repairs may be desirable.</item>
        <item name="Weakness In Plaster" number="133">The plaster finishes show evidence of weakening, as is common in many older homes.  This should be repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Amateur Installation" number="134">The installation of interior finishes is considered to be amateur quality.</item>
        <item name="Poor Workmanship" number="135">Evidence of substandard workmanship was observed.</item>
        <item name="Installation Incomplete" number="136">The installation of interior finishes is incomplete.</item>
        <item name="Mildew" number="137">Signs of mildew were observed. The cause should be investigated and/or repaired to prevent further damage.</item>
        <item name="Floors Sloping" number="138">Floor slopes are apparent. This condition could indicate greater than normal movement within the structure and potential structural problems.  Further investigation may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Floors Sagging" number="139">Sagging floors are apparent. This condition could indicate greater than normal movement within the structure and potential structural problems.  Further investigation may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Floor Movement" number="140">Movement of the floors is apparent.  Refer also to the Structural Components section of this report.</item>
        <item name="Tile Cracked" number="141">The tile floor is cracked and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Tile Cracked/Loose" number="142">The tile floor is loose and/or cracked.  This should be repaired before it becomes a trip hazard.</item>
        <item name="Tile Installation Marginal" number="143">The installation of the tile floor is less than ideal.  It is very common for tile floors to be installed without the benefit of sufficient underlayment or floor stiffening.  This can influence the long term performance of the floor.</item>
        <item name="Vinyl Seams Poor" number="144">Seams in the vinyl flooring are not in ideal condition.  Improvement is discretionary.</item>
        <item name="Vinyl Damage" number="145">The vinyl flooring is damaged and may be in need of repair or replacement.</item>
        <item name="Vinyl Poor Installation" number="146">The installation of the vinyl flooring is not ideal and may be in need of repair or replacement.</item>
        <item name="Carpet Stains" number="147">Stains were noted on the carpet.</item>
        <item name="Carpet Odor" number="148">The carpet appears to emit an odor.  Cleaning and deodorizing may be desirable.</item>
        <item name="Trim Loose" number="149">The floor trim is loose and should be re-secured.</item>
        <item name="Trim Incomplete" number="150">The installation of the floor trim is incomplete.</item>
        <item name="Stair Steep Pitch" number="151">The stairway is relatively steep. It may not be practical to change this condition. Extreme care should be taken when using this stairway. Carelessness could lead to an accident.</item>
        <item name="Stair Treads Non Standard" number="152">The size and/or orientation of the stairway "treads" may make the stairway difficult to negotiate.  This condition should be altered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Stair Risers Non Standard" number="153">The size and/or orientation of the stairway "risers" may make the stairway difficult to negotiate.  This condition should be altered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Stair Treads Loose" number="154">The stair treads were found to be loose.  This condition should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Stair Treads Damaged" number="155">The stair treads were found to be damaged.  This condition should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Curved Stair Tread Non Standard" number="156">The size and/or orientation of the curved stairway "treads" may make the stairway difficult to negotiate.  This condition should be altered for improved safety. In some cases, improvement is not cost effective.</item>
        <item name="Door Opens Into Stairwell" number="157">The door at the top of the stairwell should open away from the stairs. It is recommended that this door be altered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Spiral Stairway Unsafe" number="158">The spiral staircase is difficult to get down quickly and is thereby  dangerous in the event of a fire.  In most areas, these types of stairways are not permitted as the only means by which to get from one floor to another.</item>
        <item name="Stair Handrail Loose" number="159">Loose stairway handrails should be better secured.</item>
        <item name="Stair Handrail Needed" number="160">For improved safety, it is recommended that a railings be provided for the stairway.</item>
        <item name="Stair Railing Loose" number="161">The railing for the stairway is loose and should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Stair Railing Needed" number="162">For improved safety, it is recommended that a railing be provided for the stairway.</item>
        <item name="Railing Loose" number="163">The railing is loose and should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Railing Needed" number="164">For improved safety, it is recommended that a railing be provided.</item>
        <item name="Railing Openings" number="165">The openings in the railing are large enough to allow an object larger than four inches to fall through. It is recommended that this condition be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Railing Height" number="166">The height of the railing may not be sufficient to prevent a person from toppling over the railing. It is recommended that this condition be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="General Trimming/Adjustment" number="167">Doors should be trimmed or adjusted as necessary to work properly.</item>
        <item name="Door Hardware Damaged" number="168">Damaged or non-functional door hardware should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Doors" number="169">Damaged or non-functional doors should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Door Water Damage" number="170">Water damage was observed adjacent to the door.  The cause should be determined and repaired to ensure proper operation of the door.</item>
        <item name="Door Glass Non-Tempered" number="171">Safety glass etchings were not observed on the glass within the door.  Safety glass is required for glass doors and is generally identified by an etching in the corner of the glass pane.</item>
        <item name="General Trimming/Adjustment" number="172">Doors should be trimmed or adjusted as necessary to work properly.</item>
        <item name="Door Hardware Damaged" number="173">Damaged or non-functional door hardware should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Doors" number="174">Damaged or non-functional doors should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Door Water Damage" number="175">Water damage was observed adjacent to the door.  The cause should be determined and repaired to ensure proper operation of the door.</item>
        <item name="Door Screen Damaged" number="176">The screen for the exterior door is damaged and should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Sticking" number="177">The sliding glass door could be improved to operate freely.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Rollers" number="178">The rollers of the sliding glass door could be improved to operate freely.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Older" number="179">The sliding glass door is older.  While replacement does not represent a high priority, it may be a logical long term goal.  The function and efficiency of a new door would be a substantial improvement.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Screen Damaged" number="180">The screen for the sliding glass door is missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Screen Missing" number="181">The screen for the sliding glass door is missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Hardware Damaged" number="182">The hardware for the sliding glass door is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Lost Seal" number="183">The glass of the sliding glass door has lost its seal.  This has resulted in condensation developing between the panes of glass and can cause the glass to loose it’s insulating properties.  The glass should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Sliding Glass Leak At Threshold" number="184">Evidence of leakage was observed at the threshold of the sliding glass door.  Improved caulking would be the first step to improving this condition.</item>
        <item name="Door Glass Non-Tempered" number="185">Safety glass etchings were not observed on the glass within the door.  Safety glass is required for glass doors and is generally identified by an etching in the corner of the glass pane.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door Damage" number="186">The overhead garage door is damaged and needs repair.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door Localized Rot" number="187">The overhead garage door shows evidence of localized rot and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door Extensive Rot" number="188">The overhead garage door is substantially rotted. It should be repaired or replaced as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door Adjustment" number="189">The overhead garage door requires adjustment for easy and safe operation.</item>
        <item name="Garage Door No Safety Springs" number="190">No safety springs/cables were noted on the garage door. The installation of the springs/cables would improve safety during operation.</item>
        <item name="Garage Man Door Closer" number="191">The door between the garage and the interior of the house should be equipped with an auto-closer device to prevent automobile fumes from entering the house.</item>
        <item name="Garage Man Door Rating" number="192">The door between the garage and the interior of the house should be rated to resist fire as per local codes.</item>
        <item name="Garage Man Door Seal" number="193">The door between the garage and the interior of the house should be well sealed to prevent automobile fumes from entering the house.</item>
        <item name="Garage Man Door Adjustment" number="194">The door between the garage and the interior of the house should be adjusted to operate freely, yet fit tightly.</item>
        <item name="Old Windows - Mild Disrepair" number="195">The windows are in mild disrepair.  This is a common condition that does not necessitate immediate major repair.  Trimming and adjustment, hardware improvements and glazing repairs would be logical long term improvements.  In practice, improvements are usually made on an as needed basis only.  The most important factor is that the window exteriors are well maintained to avoid rot or water infiltration.</item>
        <item name="Low Quality - Mild Disrepair" number="196">The windows are relatively low quality.  They are in a state of mild disrepair.  Trimming and/or adjustment, hardware improvements, and weatherproofing improvements could be undertaken.  In practice, improvements are performed on an as needed basis.  Installing replacement windows may be the best long term approach.  In the interim, it is important that the window exteriors be well maintained to avoid rot or water infiltration.</item>
        <item name="Water Staining" number="197">Water staining was noted.  The cause for the staining should be determined and repairs undertaken, if necessary, to prevent structural damage.</item>
        <item name="Water Damage" number="198">ined</item>
        <item name="Window Painted Shut" number="199">The window(s) are painted shut.  Improvement can be undertaken to allow normal operation of the window.</item>
        <item name="Window Inoperative" number="200">The window(s) are inoperative. Improvement can be undertaken to allow normal operation of the window.</item>
        <item name="Window Cracked" number="201">The window(s) are cracked and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Window Broken" number="202">The window(s) are broken and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Missing Pane" number="203">The pane of glass is missing from the window should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Window Hardware Missing" number="204">Window hardware is missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Window Hardware Damaged" number="205">Window hardware is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Glass Non-Tempered" number="206">Safety glass etchings were not observed on the glass within the window(s).  This glass is required for windows close to the floor or in hazardous locations and is generally identified by an etching in the corner of the glass pane.</item>
        <item name="Lost Seal" number="207">The window(s) have lost their seal.  This has resulted in condensation developing between the panes of glass and can cause the glass to loose it’s insulating properties.  The glass should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Window Condensation" number="208">The windows show evidence of condensation.  This is not a major concern.  Controlling indoor humidity levels and/or improving window efficiency (if needed) would help to control this condition.</item>
        <item name="Window Screen(s) Damaged" number="209">The damaged screen(s) were found on the window(s) should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Window Screen(s) Missing" number="210">It may be desirable to replace window screens where missing.  The owner should be consulted regarding any screens that may be in storage.</item>
        <item name="Sash Cords Missing" number="211">Sash cords (the ropes that hold up the windows) are missing on windows.  Re-installation is necessary to ensure proper operation of the window.</item>
        <item name="Storm(s) Missing" number="212">Ideally, storm windows would be provided where missing.  The owner should be consulted regarding any storm windows that may be in storage.</item>
        <item name="Window Blocked Off" number="213">A window has been blocked off.  This should be investigated further to determine if it is weather proof.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Abandoned" number="214">Abandoned wiring should be replaced or appropriately terminated.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Damaged" number="215">Damaged wiring should be replaced or appropriately repaired.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Loose" number="216">Loose wiring should be secured.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Overheating" number="217">Overheated wiring should be repaired or replaced as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Exposed On Walls" number="218">Wiring exposed on interior finishes should be relocated or protected by a rigid conduit.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Touching Ducts/Pipes" number="219">Wiring should not touch hot air ductwork or hot water piping.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Undersized" number="220">Undersized wiring should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Inappropriate For Ext." number="221">The exterior wiring is not suited to this application.  It should be replaced with wiring suitable for outdoor use.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Extension Cords" number="222">Extension cords should not be used as permanent wiring.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Poor Connections" number="223">Improper electrical connections should be improved.  All electrical connections should be made inside junction boxes fitted with cover plates.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Junction Boxes Loose" number="224">Loose junction boxes should be properly secured.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Junction Box CVR Plates" number="225">All junction boxes should be fitted with cover plates, in order to protect the wire connections.</item>
        <item name="Wiring: Amateur Installation" number="226">The installation of the distribution wiring is non-standard.  It is suspected that installation was performed by an amateur, rather than a licensed electrician.</item>
        <item name="No Bonding On Appliances" number="227">Bonding was not found on appliances.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety hazard.</item>
        <item name="Sub Panel Location" number="228">The electrical sub panel should be moved to an appropriate location.</item>
        <item name="Sub Panel Ground/Bond" number="229">The electrical sub panel does not appear to be properly grounded/bonded.  This should be investigated and repaired.</item>
        <item name="Sub Panel Disconnect" number="230">The electrical sub panel did not have a disconnect.  This item should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Inapp. Outlets And Connectors" number="231">The aluminum wiring should be fitted with special connectors and outlets to ensure safe operation of these circuits.  During installation of this special hardware, all connections should be checked for signs of damage or overheating.  It should be pointed out that the aluminum wiring itself is a perfectly acceptable electrical conductor.  The connection points can experience overheating or become loose due to the properties of aluminum wiring.  Upon fitting the wiring with the special connectors and outlets, the wiring is considered to be safe.</item>
        <item name="Aluminum Wiring: Overheating" number="232">The aluminum wiring shows signs of overheating and should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="Alum. Wiring: Panel Not Rated" number="233">The main distribution panel does not appear to be rated for use with aluminum wiring, although there is aluminum wiring present.  This should be investigated and/or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Inoperative" number="234">An outlet is inoperative.  This outlet and circuit should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Inoperative" number="235">An outlet is inoperative.  This outlet and circuit should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Damaged" number="236">An outlet is damaged.  It should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Loose" number="237">An outlet is loose and should be re-secured.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Reversed Polarity" number="238">An outlet has reversed polarity (i.e. it is wired backwards).  This outlet and the circuit should be investigated and improved as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Ungrounded 3-Prong" number="239">Ungrounded 3-prong outlets should be improved.  This can be as simple as filling the ground slot with epoxy.  Alternatively, a grounded cable could be strung to this outlet, or a separate ground wire could be connected.  Some electrical codes allow the installation of a ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) type outlet where grounding is not provided.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Overheated" number="240">An outlet has overheated.  This outlet should be replaced and the circuit should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: GFCI Test Faulty" number="241">A ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) outlet did not respond correctly to testing during the inspection.  This receptacle should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: GFCI Inoperative" number="242">A ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) outlet is inoperative.  This circuit should be investigated and/or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: GFCI Recommended" number="243">The installation of a ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI) is recommended.  A ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI)  offers protection from shock or electrocution.</item>
        <item name="Outlets: Cover Plates" number="244">Missing outlet cover plates should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Inoperative" number="245">The inoperative light switch should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Damaged" number="246">The damaged light switch should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Loose" number="247">The loose light switch should be secured.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Obsolete" number="248">The older light switches are obsolete and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Switches: Overheated" number="249">The light switch shows evidence of overheating.  This circuit should be investigated and the switch should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Inoperative" number="250">The light is inoperative.  If the bulbs are not blown, the circuit should be investigated.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Damaged" number="251">The damaged light fixture should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Loose" number="252">The loose light fixture should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Recessed Light Bulbs" number="253">Recessed lights should be fitted with bulbs suitable to this application.  Otherwise, there is a risk of overheating and/or fire.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Recessed Light Rating" number="254">Recessed light fixtures that are installed in insulated ceilings can represent a fire hazard if they are not suitably rated for this application.  Unfortunately, it is difficult to verify that the installation has been made safely, during a home inspection.  It is recommended that a licensed electrician be engaged to verify the safety of the system.</item>
        <item name="Lights: Supported By Wiring" number="255">Light fixtures should not be supported by wiring.</item>
        <item name="Heating System Inoperative" number="256">The furnace was found to be inoperative using the normal control devices.  This should be investigated further and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Near End Of Life Cycle" number="257">Given the age of the furnace, it may be nearing the end of its useful life.  It would be wise to budget for a new furnace.</item>
        <item name="Replacement Imminent" number="258">Given the age of the furnace, replacement should be anticipated in the near future.</item>
        <item name="Premature Failure??" number="259">This particular make of furnace is prone to premature failure of the heat exchanger.  If the heat exchanger cracks or deteriorates prematurely, replacement of the heat exchanger (or the entire furnace depending of the availability of parts) will be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Octopus - Replace ASAP" number="260">It is recommended that the old "octopus" furnace be replaced.  These older systems can pose a heath risk if the heat exchanger has failed.  The improved efficiency of a new furnace would begin to offset the cost of installation immediately.  Ductwork modifications will be necessary when the furnace is upgraded.</item>
        <item name="Location Unsafe" number="261">The location of the furnace is considered unsafe.  This situation can pose a health threat and may also be a fire hazard.  A qualified heating technician should be engaged immediately to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Cracked Heat Exchanger Observed" number="262">The furnace heat exchanger was observed to cracked.  This condition is a potential health threat that should be further evaluated and/or repaired.  A qualified service technician or utility company representative should be engaged immediately.</item>
        <item name="Furnace Inaccessible" number="263">The furnace was inaccessible and could not be inspected.</item>
        <item name="Servicing Needed" number="264">The heating system requires servicing.</item>
        <item name="Blower/Motor Suspect" number="265">The blower and motor serving the heating system are in suspect condition.  This should be monitored and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Humidifier Replacement" number="266">The humidifier should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Humidifier Maintenance" number="267">The humidifier has lacked maintenance somewhat.  Cleaning and repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Air Filter Dirty" number="268">The dirty air filter should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Electronic Air Cleaner Dirty" number="269">The electronic air cleaner requires cleaning.</item>
        <item name="Elect. Air Cleaner Not Working" number="270">The electronic air cleaner did not appear to the functioning at the time of inspection.  This should be investigated and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Line Dirty" number="271">The condensate line leading from the furnace appears dirty.  This condition should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Pump Inoperative" number="272">The furnace condensate pump is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Fan Limit Adjustment" number="273">The fan limit switch appears to require adjustment.</item>
        <item name="Fan Limit Inoperative" number="274">The fan limit switch did not respond properly upon testing.  This represents a potential safety concern and should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Combustion Air Lacking" number="275">The supply of combustion air (and draft air) for the heating system may be insufficient.  This condition represents a health hazard that should be investigated and/or repaired immediately.  Additional combustion air can usually be provided without a great deal of difficulty or expense.</item>
        <item name="Burner Old" number="276">The burner is older.  It is difficult to predict the useful remaining life of this unit.</item>
        <item name="Burner Suspect" number="277">The burner is in suspect condition.  It should be evaluated by a qualified licensed heating technician and improved as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Burner Dirty/Soot" number="278">Soot build up and debris were observed on or around the burner.  Cleaning and servicing are recommended.</item>
        <item name="Burner Rust" number="279">The burner shows evidence of corrosion.  This condition should be evaluated and/or repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Deposits" number="280">There was a noticeable quantity of deposits visible in the gas furnace.  This is a residue from the reaction of gas combustion and galvanized steel.  These deposits are not unusual but can be an indication of lack of periodic cleaning and maintenance.</item>
        <item name="Flashback" number="281">The heating system shows evidence of "flashback" (ignited gas spilling out at the front of the furnace at start up).  This condition should be evaluated and/or repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Pilot Problems?" number="282">Evidence suggests that problems have been experienced in past with the pilot light. This condition should be evaluated and/or repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Back Drafting" number="283">The heating system shows evidence that exhaust products have been "back drafting".  This is a health concern and should be repaired immediately.  This condition may be the result of insufficient combustion/draft air, inappropriate flue and chimney configuration, obstructions within the chimney or exhaust flue, or a problem with the furnace itself.  A qualified licensed heating technician should be consulted.</item>
        <item name="Gas Line Material" number="284">Inappropriate material is being used for the furnace gas lines.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Gas Valve Location" number="285">A valve for the furnace gas line is in an inappropriate location.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="No Gas Shut-Off" number="286">No shut-off for the furnace gas line was found.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Furnace Gas Leak" number="287">A leak was detected in the furnace gas lines.  This should be repaired immediately as it poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative Heater" number="288">The baseboard heater was found to be inoperative using the normal control devices.  This should be investigated further and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="No Source of Heat" number="289">No heat source was found.  It may be desirable to install a baseboard heater in this location.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Heater" number="290">A damaged heater was observed.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Rusted Heater" number="291">Baseboard heater(s) show evidence of corrosion. Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Control Damaged" number="292">Baseboard heater controls are damaged and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Old Heaters" number="293">The baseboard heaters are older.  Their reliability may be reduced.  Replacement units may be necessary over time.</item>
        <item name="Condensation/Vent Problems" number="294">As with many homes that are electrically heated, there is evidence of condensation and ventilation difficulties.  This condition should be monitored and/or repaired.  If this proves to be a problem, steps should be taken to better control humidity and improve air change within the house.  This could be as simple as installing exhaust fans.  A more sophisticated measure would be to install a heat recovery ventilator.</item>
        <item name="Wiring Unsafe" number="295">Unsafe electric heater wiring was observed.  For safety reasons, this should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative System" number="296">The air conditioning system was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate of this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Old System" number="297">As is not uncommon for homes of this age and location, the air conditioning system is older.  It may require a slightly higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to major component breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.</item>
        <item name="Very Old System" number="298">As is not uncommon for homes of this age and location, the air conditioning system is relatively old.  It will require a higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to major component breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.  If the compressor fails, or if breakdowns become chronic, replacing the entire system may be more cost-effective than continuing to undertake repairs.</item>
        <item name="System Obsolete" number="299">The air conditioning system is obsolete and should be replaced (assuming central air conditioning is desired).</item>
        <item name="Undersized System?" number="300">The capacity of the air conditioning system may prove to be marginal during the warmer days of the summer.  Without performing detailed heat gain calculations, or living in the home during warm summer days, actual conditions are difficult to predict.  No improvements are recommended at this time.</item>
        <item name="Temperature Drop Excessive" number="301">The temperature drop measured across the evaporator coil of the air conditioning system is greater than considered normal.  This indicates that air flow across the evaporator coil is too low.  Low air flow could be the result of a dirty filter, dirty or obstructed evaporator coil fins, or insufficient blower and/or ductwork sizing.  This condition can lead to ice build-up on the coil.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Temperature Drop Insufficient" number="302">The temperature drop measured across the evaporator coil of the air conditioning system is lower than considered typical.  This usually indicates that servicing is needed.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Service Needed" number="303">The air conditioning system requires servicing.</item>
        <item name="Insulation Damage On Ref. Lines" number="304">Damaged insulation on refrigerant lines should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Return Chase Location" number="305">The return chase/vent for the air conditioning system is in an improper location.  This vent should be situated away from any gas pipes, sewer vents, refrigerant piping or electrical wiring.</item>
        <item name="Outdoor Unit Out Of Level" number="306">The outdoor unit of the air conditioning system is out of level.  This should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Outdoor Unit Dirty" number="307">The outdoor unit of the air conditioning system requires cleaning.</item>
        <item name="Outdoor Unit Fin Damage" number="308">The fins of the outdoor portion of the air conditioning system were observed to be damaged and in need of repair.  This condition can reduce the efficiency of the system.</item>
        <item name="Outdoor Unit Noisy" number="309">The outdoor unit of the air conditioning system is noisy.  This should be investigated during servicing.</item>
        <item name="Cut Back Vegetation" number="310">Vegetation in the vicinity of the outdoor unit of the air conditioning system should be cut back.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Tray Leak" number="311">Evidence of prior leakage was observed at the condensate tray of the air conditioning system.  Repairs should be undertaken, if necessary</item>
        <item name="Cond. Discharge Location Poor" number="312">The discharge location of the condensate line for the air conditioning system should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Line Blocked" number="313">The air conditioning condensate line appears to be obstructed.  Minor improvements are needed.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative Condensate Pump" number="314">The condensate pump was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  Further investigation and/or repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Trap Needed" number="315">Condensate lines for air conditioning systems that flow into sanitary drains should be "trapped" to avoid the potential for contamination.</item>
        <item name="Condensate Line Insulation" number="316">Damaged insulation on condensate lines should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Drip Pan Needed" number="317">In order to reduce the potential for water damage, it is recommended that an auxiliary drain pan be installed below the indoor component of the air conditioning system.</item>
        <item name="Drip Pan Undersized" number="318">The auxiliary drain pan installed below the of the air conditioning system is undersized and should be repaired</item>
        <item name="Drip Pan Water/Debris" number="319">The auxiliary drain pan installed below the of the air conditioning system contains water and debris.  This should be emptied and cleaned.</item>
        <item name="Indoor Fan Noisy/Vibrates" number="320">The indoor fan is excessively noisy.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Indoor Fan Undersized?" number="321">The indoor fan may be undersized.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Electrical Conductor Size" number="322">The electrical service for the air conditioning unit is undersized and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Over Current Protection" number="323">The over current protection for the air conditioning unit is undersized and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="One Speed" number="324">The evaporative cooler is a one speed model.</item>
        <item name="Two Speed" number="325">The evaporative cooler is a two speed model.</item>
        <item name="Lacking Maintenance" number="326">The evaporative cooler has been lacking maintenance somewhat.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Older System" number="327">As is not uncommon for homes of this age and location, the evaporative cooler is older.  It may require a higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to component breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.</item>
        <item name="Obsolete Unit" number="328">The evaporative cooler is obsolete and should be replaced (assuming air conditioning is desired).</item>
        <item name="Inoperative Cooler" number="329">The evaporative cooler was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Noisy Motor" number="330">The motor serving the evaporative cooler is noisy.   A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Housing Damaged" number="331">The exterior housing of the evaporative cooler is damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Fan Belt/Pulley Repair" number="332">The fan belt/pulleys within the evaporative cooler are damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Fan Rust" number="333">The rust is being built up within the evaporative cooler and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Water Supply Line" number="334">The water supply line for the evaporative cooler is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Air Gap Too Small" number="335">The air gap between the water level and float in the evaporative cooler is too small (a minimum  of a one inch air gap is required).  This item should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Float Valve Suspect" number="336">The float valve for the evaporative cooler is in suspect condition.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Spray Nozzle Restricted" number="337">The evaporative cooler spray nozzle appears to be restricted and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Pump Suspect" number="338">The pump for the evaporative cooler is in suspect condition.  A qualified heating and cooling technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Water Pads/Blankets Dirty" number="339">The water pads/blanket utilized by the evaporative cooler are dirty and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Roof Jacks Marginal" number="340">The roof jacks are in marginal condition.  Improvement will likely be necessary over the next few years.</item>
        <item name="Roof Jacks Poor" number="341">The roof jacks are in poor condition.  A qualified licensed contractor should be contacted to evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Excess Humidity In House" number="342">Operation of the evaporative cooler appears to have resulted in excess humidity on the interior of the home.  A qualified licensed contractor should be contacted to evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Loose Thermostat" number="343">The thermostat should be better secured and leveled.</item>
        <item name="Old" number="344">The thermostat is older and may prove to be temperamental.  Replacement is a minor job.</item>
        <item name="Location" number="345">The location of the thermostat is less than ideal.  It may be subject to inconsistent temperatures.  Relocating the thermostat is a minor job.</item>
        <item name="Low Flow" number="346">Supply air flow is considered less than ideal.  Rebalancing the ductwork may improve this situation.</item>
        <item name="Balancing Needed" number="347">Balancing of the ductwork is recommended to improve the distribution.</item>
        <item name="Proximity Of Furnace Poor" number="348">The proximity of the furnace to the ductwork is such that air flow to certain areas of the home will be less than ideal.</item>
        <item name="Duct Cleaning Needed" number="349">Duct cleaning is recommended.</item>
        <item name="Seal Opening" number="350">Loose fitting joints and/or openings in the ductwork should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Old Ducts Undersized" number="351">As is common in older homes, the ductwork is not ideally configured.  This may inhibit distribution slightly, and may not be conducive to proper distribution of cool air, if air conditioning is employed.</item>
        <item name="Rusted Ducts Below Slab" number="352">The ductwork installed below the concrete slab shows evidence of rusting.  This would suggest the presence of moisture in the ducts, which can also be a health hazard.  It is impossible to predict the condition of the ducts below the slab.  It may ultimately become necessary to abandon these ducts in favor of another means of heat distribution.</item>
        <item name="Motorized Dampers Suspect" number="353">Motorized dampers have been provided in the ductwork.  These dampers are typically operated by thermostats in different areas of the home.  The dampers open as the thermostats call for heat.  Most motorized damper systems are neglected over time and eventually break down.  They are often abandoned.</item>
        <item name="Improper Duct Material" number="354">The material being used for the ducts is inappropriate and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Duct Routing" number="355">The routing of the ductwork could be re-configured as it is now prone to potential damage.</item>
        <item name="No Return Air Vent At" number="356">No return air vent is visible.  Installing a return air vent in this location is not considered critical; however, it would improve heat distribution, and facilitate better cooling (if air conditioning is utilized).</item>
        <item name="No Return Flow" number="357">No return air flow was detectable from the vent.  This would suggest that the return air passageway is obstructed.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Return Vent Near Furnace" number="358">A return vent is situated relatively close to the furnace.  This arrangement is a safety concern, as it may be conducive to back drafting of the furnace exhaust.  Improvement is a minor task and should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Improper Duct Material" number="359">The material being used for the ducts is inappropriate and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Duct Routing" number="360">The routing of the ductwork could be re-configured as it is now prone to potential damage.</item>
        <item name="Flue Connections" number="361">Poor exhaust flue connections should be repaired immediately.</item>
        <item name="Vent Material Inappropriate" number="362">The exhaust vent material appears to be inappropriate to this application.  This condition should be repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Flue Slope" number="363">The slope of the exhaust flue does not appear to be sufficient to allow the safe flow of exhaust gases.  This condition should be evaluated and repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Flue Clearance" number="364">There is insufficient clearance between the exhaust flue and combustible materials.  This is a fire hazard.  This condition should be evaluated and repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Flue Termination Improper" number="365">The termination of the exhaust flue is improper.  This is a fire hazard.  This condition should be repaired by a qualified licensed heating technician.</item>
        <item name="Induced Draft Fan Suspect" number="366">The induced draft fan serving the heating system is in suspect condition.  These fans have a reputation for breakdown.</item>
        <item name="Barometric Damper Improvement" number="367">The barometric damper on the exhaust flue requires improvement to ensure safe emission of exhaust products.</item>
        <item name="Pressure Regulator Needed" number="368">As the static water pressure of the supply plumbing system exceeds 80 pounds per square inch (psi), it would be wise to install a pressure regulator.  Otherwise, the plumbing system may be prone to leaks in piping, fittings or other equipment.</item>
        <item name="Older Steel" number="369">The older steel piping is subject to corrosion on the interior of the pipe.  As corrosion builds up, the inside diameter of the pipe becomes constricted, resulting in a loss of water pressure.  This piping is typically replaced when the loss of pressure can no longer be tolerated.</item>
        <item name="Leak" number="370">The supply piping is leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Exterior Corrosion" number="371">Corrosion on the exterior of the supply piping was observed.</item>
        <item name="Support Lacking" number="372">The supply pipe lacks adequate support and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Water Pressure Low" number="373">Water pressure was found to be low when tested with two fixtures operated simultaneously.  This condition should be investigated and/or repaired.</item>
        <item name="Handle Missing" number="374">A supply valve handle is missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Handle Damaged" number="375">The installation of the supply piping is not workmanlike and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Pipe Hammer" number="376">Water hammer in the supply piping was observed when operating plumbing fixtures.  Over time, this condition can influence the integrity of pipe connections.  Closing valves and faucets slowly is one approach to avoiding water hammer.  Better securing pipes (where possible) and installing air chambers (shock absorbers) at the risers to fixtures would be another solution.</item>
        <item name="Workmanship Marginal" number="377">The installation of the supply piping is not workmanlike.</item>
        <item name="Condensation On Cold Pipe" number="378">If condensation of the cold water piping becomes a problem, this piping could be insulated.</item>
        <item name="Cross Connection" number="379">A "cross connection" was observed.  A cross connection exists whenever there is potential for potable water to contact a source of contamination.  This condition should be repaired as is poses a potential health concern.</item>
        <item name="Softened Water As Drink. Water" number="380">It is advised that drinking water supply piping bypass the water softener.  Sodium rich water can be harmful to plants and to your health.</item>
        <item name="Well Pump Older" number="381">The water pump is older.  As with any older mechanical device, it is impossible to predict its useful remaining life.</item>
        <item name="Pump/Tank Poor Setup" number="382">The water pump and pressure tank configuration are makeshift at best.  Improvement is advisable.</item>
        <item name="Waterlogged Holding Tank?" number="383">It is suspected that the pressure tank serving the water pump is "waterlogged".  Servicing is needed.</item>
        <item name="Older Fixtures" number="384">The majority of plumbing fixtures are older.</item>
        <item name="Poor Quality Installation" number="385">The installation of the plumbing fixtures has been performed in a non workmanlike fashion and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Hot/Cold Reversed" number="386">The hot and cold faucets are reversed and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Leaky" number="387">The faucet(s) are leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Loose" number="388">The faucet is loose and should be tightened.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Stiff" number="389">The faucet is stiff and should be improved.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Inoperative" number="390">The faucet is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Faucets Aging" number="391">The faucets are showing signs of age.  Updating faucets over time should be anticipated.</item>
        <item name="Faucet Mineral Build Up" number="392">Mineral build up was observed at faucets.  This may suggest "hard" water.  Continued build up at faucets and within pipes could affect the performance of the supply plumbing system.  Water conditioning equipment could be considered.  This situation should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="Sink Damaged" number="393">The sink is damaged and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Sink Cracked" number="394">The sink is cracked and needs repair.</item>
        <item name="Sink Drains Slow" number="395">The sink was observed to drain slowly, suggesting that an obstruction may exist.</item>
        <item name="Sink Stopper Missing" number="396">The drainstop for the sink is missing and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Sink Stopper Inoperative" number="397">The drainstop for the sink is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Loose" number="398">The toilet is loose and should be re-secured.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Prior Leak" number="399">The toilet shows evidence of prior leakage.  This should be investigated to determine if any structural damage has occurred or whether the leak is still active.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Floor Damage" number="400">The floor adjacent to the toilet shows evidence of water damage.  This condition should be repaired before further structural damage occurs.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Cracked" number="401">The toilet is cracked and should, ideally, be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Slow Flush" number="402">The toilet was observed to flush slowly at the time of the inspection.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Inoperative" number="403">The toilet is inoperative and should be repaired or replaced.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Runs On" number="404">The toilet runs on after flushing.  Improvement to the tank mechanism is likely to be needed.</item>
        <item name="Toilet Old" number="405">The toilet is old.  Replacement may be necessary.</item>
        <item name="Shower Head Leak" number="406">The shower head is leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Shower Head Poor" number="407">The shower head is in poor condition.  Replacement may become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Tile Grout/Caulk" number="408">Cracked, deteriorated and/or missing shower stall grout and caulk should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Tile Damage" number="409">The tile shower stall requires repair.  Loose or damaged tile, grout and caulk should be repaired or replaced as necessary.  Any damage to the wall behind the tile should also be repaired (if necessary).  Further investigation may reveal the need to rebuild a portion of the shower stall.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Rebuild Tile Base" number="410">The base of the shower stall should be rebuilt.  Wall or floor damage beneath the enclosure should also be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Complete Rebuild" number="411">The shower stall should be rebuilt.  Replacement with an acrylic or fiberglass unit should be considered.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Drains Slow" number="412">The shower stall was observed to drain slowly, suggesting that an obstruction may exist.</item>
        <item name="Shower Stall Leak" number="413">The shower enclosure was found to be leaking.  This should be repaired before water damage to the structure occurs.</item>
        <item name="Shower Door Defective" number="414">The shower stall door is defective and should be repaired or replaced as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Laundry Tub Old Concrete" number="415">The older concrete laundry tub appears serviceable; however, it should be monitored for leakage.</item>
        <item name="Laundry Tub Cracked" number="416">The laundry tub is cracked and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Laundry Tub Leak" number="417">The laundry tub leaks.  Repair or replacement should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Laundry Tub Loose" number="418">The laundry tub is loose and should be properly secured.</item>
        <item name="Hose Bib Leaks" number="419">The hose bib is leaking and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Hose Bib Inoperative" number="420">The hose bib is inoperative and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Hose Bib Shut Off Needed" number="421">An isolating valve should be installed for the hose bib (exterior faucet).</item>
        <item name="Hose Bib Anti-Siphon Needed" number="422">It is recommended that an anti-siphon device be added to the hose bib(s).</item>
        <item name="Marginal Workmanship" number="423">The installation of the waste piping is not workmanlike and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Pipe Leak" number="424">The waste piping is leaking and is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Obstruction" number="425">It is suspected that the waste piping is obstructed.  Further investigation and/or repair is needed.</item>
        <item name="Trap Leak" number="426">The trap is leaking and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Trap Suspect" number="427">The trap is in suspect condition.  This area should be monitored.</item>
        <item name="S Trap" number="428">An "S" trap has been used.  Ideally, S traps should be replaced as they are subject to siphoning problems.  S traps are common in older homes.  Replacement is sometimes difficult and thus the S traps are usually tolerated.  Care should be taken to keep the trap "primed".  Fixtures should be monitored for sewer odor.</item>
        <item name="Insufficient Slope" number="429">The waste piping does not have sufficient slope for proper drainage.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Support Insufficient" number="430">The waste piping should be better supported.</item>
        <item name="ABS Pipe Suspect" number="431">The ABS black plastic waste piping may be a defective product.  Connections should be monitored for leakage.  Repair or replacement may become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Connection Suspect" number="432">The waste piping connection is suspect. Repair or replacement may become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Older Piping" number="433">For the most part, the waste piping is older.  It may be prone to unexpected problems.  Improvement is recommended on an as needed basis.</item>
        <item name="Lead Pipe" number="434">The lead waste piping is older and prone to leakage at the connections.</item>
        <item name="Main Clean Out Not Found" number="435">No clean out for the main drain was found.  Clean outs are useful when attempting to remove obstructions within the drainage piping.  It may be prudent to have a clean out installed now, or verify its location with the existing owner.</item>
        <item name="Odor" number="436">A sewer odor was detected.  This usually suggests that the fixture is not properly vented, or that the trap has dried out.  This area should be monitored.  If odor persists, a plumber should be engaged.</item>
        <item name="Openings" number="437">Unsealed opening in the waste piping should be corrected.</item>
        <item name="Venting Suspect" number="438">The presence of sufficient venting for the waste piping is suspect. This should be investigated further and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Stack Height/Size Insufficient" number="439">The vent stack that penetrates the roof should extend at least 6 inches above the roof and should be at least 2 inches in diameter.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Old Unit" number="440">The water heater is an older unit that may be approaching the end of its useful life.  It would be wise to budget for a new unit.  One cannot predict with certainty when replacement will become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Unit Middle Aged" number="441">Water heaters have a typical life expectancy of 7 to 12 years.  The existing unit is approaching this age range.  One cannot predict with certainty when replacement will become necessary.</item>
        <item name="Leakage Evidence" number="442">The water heater shows evidence of prior leakage.  This should be carefully monitored and repairs undertaken, if necessary.</item>
        <item name="Needs Service" number="443">It is recommended that the water heater be serviced.</item>
        <item name="Corrosion At Supply Connections" number="444">The supply piping shows evidence of corrosion where it meets the water heater.  This is a common condition and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Reversed Hot And Cold" number="445">The hot and cold supply water connections are reversed at the water heater.  For improved operation, this condition should be corrected.</item>
        <item name="No Shut Off Valve" number="446">There is no shut off valve on the cold water supply to the water heater.  It is suggested that one be installed.</item>
        <item name="No TPR Valve" number="447">For safety reasons, it is recommended that a Temperature and Pressure Relief (TPR) Valve be installed for the water heater.  The lack of such a valve is a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Leaky TPR Valve" number="448">The Temperature and Pressure Relief (TPR) Valve serving the water heater is leaking slightly.  Minor repairs or cleaning can usually rectify this condition.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative TPR Valve" number="449">The Temperature and Pressure Relief (TPR) Valve serving the water heater is inoperative.  This condition should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Discharge Tube Needs Improve." number="450">The discharge piping serving the Temperature and Pressure Relief (TPR) Valve for the water heater should terminate not less than 6 inches or more than 24 inches above the floor.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="No Safety Pan" number="451">No safety pan and drain was found for the water heater.  This should be repaired by the installation of a pan with a drain by a qualified professional</item>
        <item name="Wiring Needs Conduit" number="452">Wiring serving the electric water heater should be protected by a conduit.</item>
        <item name="Wiring Improvement" number="453">The electrical wiring connected to the water heater is in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Missing Cover" number="454">The cover is missing from the water heater burner chamber.  This should be replaced for reasons of safety and efficient combustion.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Cover" number="455">The cover is damaged for the water heater burner chamber.  This should be replaced for reasons of safety and efficient combustion.</item>
        <item name="Missing Controls" number="456">Controls for the water heater are missing and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Damaged Controls" number="457">Controls for the water heater are damaged and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Casing Damage" number="458">The exterior casing of the water heater is damaged.  This should be repaired in the interest of safety and to prevent possible leaking.</item>
        <item name="Burner Dirty" number="459">The water heater burner is dirty.  It should be cleaned and adjusted.</item>
        <item name="Spillage Of Exhaust" number="460">The water heater venting system shows evidence of exhaust "spillage".  This is a serious condition that could be a health threat to the occupants of the home.  This condition should be addressed promptly.</item>
        <item name="Combustion Air" number="461">It is suspected that there is an insufficient supply of combustion air for the water heater.  Improvement is usually straightforward, and should be considered high priority for safety reasons.</item>
        <item name="Draft Diverter Improvement" number="462">The "draft diverter" of the water heater venting system is configured in such a way that it could allow spillage of exhaust products.  This is a potential safety concern that should be addressed promptly.</item>
        <item name="Vent Pipe Aluminum" number="463">The vent pipe serving the water heater appears to be made of aluminum.  This material is not well suited to this application and, for safety reasons, it should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Vent Pipe Clearance" number="464">The vent pipe serving the water heater does not have safe clearance from combustible materials.  This condition should be improved for safety reasons.</item>
        <item name="Vent Pipe Connections" number="465">For enhanced safety, it is recommended that the connections of the water heater venting system be improved.</item>
        <item name="WH Gas Line Material" number="466">Inappropriate material is being used for the water heater gas line.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="WH Gas Valve Location" number="467">A valve for the water heater gas line is in an inappropriate location.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="WH No Gas Shut-Off" number="468">No shut-off for the water heater gas line was found.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Water Heater Gas Leak" number="469">A leak was detected in the water heater gas line.  This should be repaired immediately as it poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Protection From Damage" number="470">Given the location of the water heater, it should be better protected from physical damage.</item>
        <item name="Garage Clearances Need Improve." number="471">Water heaters in garages should be on a raised platform so that the pilots, burner or heating elements are not closer than 18 inches from the garage floor.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Unsafe Location" number="472">The location of the water heater is considered unsafe.  This situation should be remedied for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Improve Mount" number="473">The stand under the water heater does not appear to adequately support the tank safely.  Rebuilding or modifying is recommended.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="OUTDOOR COOKING EQUIPMENT COMMENTS" number="441">
        <item name="Energy Source: Gas" number="1">Energy source: Gas</item>
        <item name="Energy Source: Electricity" number="2">Energy source: Electricity</item>
        <item name="Unit Unstable" number="3">The equipment was found to be unstable and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative" number="4">This component was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  Further investigation and/or repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Defective" number="5">This component was defective at the time of the inspection.  Repair or replacement should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Damaged" number="6">This component was observed to be damaged and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Older" number="7">This component is older.  It may require a slightly higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.</item>
        <item name="Obsolete" number="8">This component is obsolete and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Unsafe" number="9">This component is considered to be unsafe.  For safety reasons, it should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="Missing" number="10">This component was missing at the time of the inspection.  It should be provided to ensure proper function.</item>
        <item name="Improper Wiring" number="11">This component was observed to be improperly wired and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Maintenance Lacking" number="12">This component has been lacking maintenance somewhat.  A qualified technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="OCE - Gas Line Material" number="13">Inappropriate material is being used for the gas lines.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="OCE - Gas Valve Location" number="14">A valve for the gas line is in an inappropriate location.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="OCE - No Gas Shut-Off" number="15">No shut-off for the gas line was found.  This should be repaired as it poses a potential safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Gas Leak" number="16">A gas leak was detected.  This is a serious safety concern.  It is recommended that the gas utility be engaged immediately.  The current occupants of the home should be notified.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="GAS LINES COMMENTS" number="442">
        <item name="Gas Leak" number="1">A gas leak was detected.  This is a serious safety concern.  It is recommended that the gas utility be engaged immediately.  The current occupants of the home should be notified.</item>
        <item name="Main Shutoff Not Found" number="2">The main gas shut off valve was not found during the inspection.  This valve should at all times be readily accessible.  The current owner or the gas utility should be consulted.</item>
        <item name="Main Shutoff Obstructed" number="3">Access to the main gas shut off valve is obstructed.  This valve should at all times be readily accessible.  Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Gas Meter Not Protected" number="4">The gas meter should be better protected against mechanical damage.</item>
        <item name="Copper Unsuitable" number="5">The copper gas piping is not suitable to this application.  Repairs and replacement should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Plastic Unsuitable" number="6">The plastic gas piping is not suitable to above grade installation. Repairs and replacement should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Clear. From Ground Insufficient" number="7">The gas piping should have at least 6 inches of clearance from grade. Repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Corrosion" number="8">Evidence of corrosion of the gas piping was observed.  The gas utility should be consulted and repairs undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Union Location" number="9">The "union" in the gas piping is not suitably located and should be repaired.  Unions in gas piping should only be found at meters and at appliances after the shut off valve.</item>
        <item name="Poor Appliance Connection" number="10">The appliance gas connection is unconventional.  This condition should be repaired for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="Shut Off Valve Needed" number="11">A gas shut off valve is needed.  Repairs should be undertaken</item>
        <item name="Drip Leg Needed" number="12">A "drip leg" is normally required for gas appliance connections.  This should be investigated and repairs undertaken as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Undergrnd Pipe Protect. Suspect" number="13">It is questionable whether the underground gas piping is suitably protected from corrosion.  The gas utility should be consulted and repairs undertaken as necessary.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations VI-8" number="14">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to inspect sacrificial anode bonding or for its existence.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="WATER WELL COMMENTS" number="443">
        <item name="Type Of Pump" number="1">Type of pump: ???</item>
        <item name="Type Of Storage Equipment" number="2">Type of storage equipment: ???</item>
        <item name="Proximity To Septic System" number="3">A existing septic system was found to be within ??? feet of the well. This should be investigated to determine if it poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Septic System Too Close" number="4">The well was found to be too close to an existing septic system.  This should be investigated and repaired as is poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative" number="5">This component was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  Further investigation and/or repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Defective" number="6">This component was defective at the time of the inspection.  Repair or replacement should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Damaged" number="7">This component was observed to be damaged and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Older" number="8">This component is older.  It may require a slightly higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.</item>
        <item name="Obsolete" number="9">This component is obsolete and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Unsafe" number="10">This component is considered to be unsafe.  For safety reasons, it should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="Missing" number="11">This component was missing at the time of the inspection.  It should be provided to ensure proper function.</item>
        <item name="Improper Wiring" number="12">This component was observed to be improperly wired and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Maintenance Lacking" number="13">This component has been lacking maintenance somewhat.  A qualified technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations VI-D" number="14">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to excavate or uncover the system or its components; determine the reliability of the water supply or source; or locate or verify underground water leaks.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="SEPTIC SYSTEM COMMENTS" number="444">
        <item name="Type Of Septic System" number="1">Type of system: ???</item>
        <item name="Location Of Drainfield" number="2">Location of drainfield: ???</item>
        <item name="Vis. Efflnt. Seepage Over Tank" number="3">Visible effluent seepage over tank.  This condition should be investigated further and repairs undertaken, as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Vis. Efflnt. Seepage Over Field" number="4">Visible effluent seepage over field. This condition should be investigated further and repairs undertaken, as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Proximity To ???" number="5">The septic system was found to be within ??? feet of ???. This should be investigated to determine if it poses a safety concern.</item>
        <item name="No Access To Tank" number="6">The septic tank had no visible access.  This should be investigated and repaired.</item>
        <item name="Inoperative" number="7">This component was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  Further investigation and/or repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Defective" number="8">This component was defective at the time of the inspection.  Repair or replacement should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Damaged" number="9">This component was observed to be damaged and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Older" number="10">This component is older.  It may require a slightly higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.</item>
        <item name="Obsolete" number="11">This component is obsolete and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Unsafe" number="12">This component is considered to be unsafe.  For safety reasons, it should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="Missing" number="13">This component was missing at the time of the inspection.  It should be provided to ensure proper function.</item>
        <item name="Improper Wiring" number="14">This component was observed to be improperly wired and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Maintenance Lacking" number="15">This component has been lacking maintenance somewhat.  A qualified technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations VI-E" number="16">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to excavate or uncover the system or its components; determine the size, adequacy, or efficiency of the system; or determine the type of construction used.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="SECURITY SYSTEM COMMENTS" number="445">
        <item name="Security System Inoperative" number="1">The security system is inoperative.  Repairs should be undertaken, as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Security System Older" number="2">The security system is an older system.  Reliability and performance may not be ideal.</item>
        <item name="Security System Needs Repair" number="3">The security system is in need of a variety of repairs to function properly.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="FIRE PROTECTION EQUIPMENT COMMENTS" number="446">
        <item name="Type Of Fire Protect. System" number="1">Type of fire protection system: ???</item>
        <item name="Inoperative" number="2">This component was inoperative at the time of the inspection.  Further investigation and/or repairs should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Defective" number="3">This component was defective at the time of the inspection.  Repair or replacement should be undertaken.</item>
        <item name="Damaged" number="4">This component was observed to be damaged and in need of repair.</item>
        <item name="Older" number="5">This component is older.  It may require a slightly higher level of maintenance, and may be more prone to breakdown.  Predicting the frequency or time frame for repairs on any mechanical device is virtually impossible.</item>
        <item name="Obsolete" number="6">This component is obsolete and should be replaced.</item>
        <item name="Unsafe" number="7">This component is considered to be unsafe.  For safety reasons, it should be repaired promptly.</item>
        <item name="Missing" number="8">This component was missing at the time of the inspection.  It should be provided to ensure proper function.</item>
        <item name="Improper Wiring" number="9">This component was observed to be improperly wired and should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Maintenance Lacking" number="10">This component has been lacking maintenance somewhat.  A qualified technician should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
    </infobutton>
    <infobutton description="(tx) Summary Foundation Description" number="492">
        <item name="performing as intended.  No significant problems were observed" number="1">performing as intended. No significant problems were observed</item>
        <item name="not performing as intended.  See additional comments below." number="2">not performing as intended. See additional comments below.</item>
        <item name="in need of major repair.  See additional comments below" number="3">in need of major repair. See additional comments below</item>
        <item name="in need of complete replacement.  See additional comments below" number="4">in need of complete replacement. See additional comments below</item>
        <item name="Cracks Minor/Settling" number="1">Common minor cracks were observed in the foundation walls of the house. This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses. New Item Need to be redefined</item>
        <item name="Cracks Minor/Shrinkage" number="2">Minor vertical cracking was observed in the foundation. This type of cracking is usually the result of shrinkage of the concrete as it cures. Shrinkage cracks are very common and should not be cause for alarm.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Moderate/Settling" number="3">Slightly greater than typical foundation cracking was observed. The amount of movement does not suggest a serious structural problem. This area should, of course, be monitored. The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection.</item>
        <item name="Cracks Major/Settling" number="4">Substantial foundation cracking was observed. This implies that structural movement of the building has occurred. The rate of movement cannot be predicted during a one-time inspection. A structural engineer should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Spalling (Exterior)" number="5">Surface deterioration (known as spalling) was observed on the exterior of the exposed foundation walls. This condition is common in many homes and does not usually represent a structural concern. In an effort to prevent long term deterioration, it would be wise to consider parging deteriorated areas. Lot drainage improvements, as outlined in the "Exterior" section of this report are also recommended.</item>
        <item name="Mortar Deterioration (Exterior)" number="6">Foundation wall mortar joints show evidence of deterioration. It would be wise to consider repointing deteriorated areas in order to improve durability.</item>
        <item name="Backfill Height Excessive" number="7">The height of the backfill (soil adjacent to the foundation) appears to exceed the acceptable limit. This could result in excessive force on the foundation. A structural engineer or qualified contractor should be consulted to further evaluate this condition and the remedies available for correction.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Exterior Wall Cracks" number="8">Cracks were observed on the exterior walls of the house. This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Interior Wall Cracks" number="9">Cracks were observed on the interior walls of the house. This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Door Frames" number="10">Door frames were found to be out-of-square within house. This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Movement - Floor Slope" number="11">Sloping floors were observed within house. This implies that some structural movement of the building has occurred, as is typical of most houses.</item>
        <item name="Cable Ends Visible" number="12">Post tension cable ends were observed on the exterior of the foundation. This should be repaired to prevent corrosion.</item>
        <item name="Wood Debris /Trash" number="13">All wood debris and/or trash should be removed from the crawl space.</item>
        <item name="Wood/Soil Contact" number="14">Crawl space wood/soil contact should be eliminated. This condition is conducive to rot and wood boring insect activity.</item>
        <item name="Seal Openings" number="15">All potential vermin entry points to the crawl space should be sealed.</item>
        <item name="Vermin Activity" number="16">There is evidence of vermin activity in the crawl space. A pest control specialist should be consulted in this regard.</item>
        <item name="Secure Ducting" number="17">Loose ductwork in the crawl space should be repaired.</item>
        <item name="Past/Seasonal Water" number="18">There is evidence of past water in the crawl space. This condition may vary seasonally and/or with precipitation intensity. Lot drainage improvements should be addressed as a first step to controlling water in the crawl space. This condition should then be monitored to determine if drainage tiles are necessary.</item>
        <item name="Wall Vent Obstructed" number="19">Obstructed crawl space wall vents should be cleared or opened.</item>
        <item name="Missing/Damaged Screens" number="20">Missing or damaged crawl space vent screens should be repaired as necessary.</item>
        <item name="Ventilation Needed" number="21">Ventilation of the crawl space is insufficient. One (1) square foot of free vent area should be provided for every five hundred (500) square feet of crawl space. Proper ventilation will help to control humidity and reduce the potential for rot. Crawl spaces can be vented to the building interior or exterior, depending on the configuration of the crawl space.</item>
        <item name="Mildew Due To Poor Ventilation" number="22">Evidence of mildew was observed in the crawl space. This is suspected to be related to improper ventilation. One (1) square foot of free vent area should be provided for every five hundred (500) square feet of crawl space. Proper ventilation will help to control humidity and reduce the potential for rot. Crawl spaces can be vented to the building interior or exterior, depending on the configuration of the crawl space.</item>
        <item name="Adjust Moisture Barrier" number="23">The crawl space moisture barrier should be spread out to cover all exposed soil.</item>
        <item name="Repair Moisture Barrier" number="24">The crawl space moisture barrier should be repaired where damaged or incomplete.</item>
        <item name="Moisture Barrier Needed" number="25">A moisture barrier should be installed on the crawl space floor.</item>
        <item name="Foam Board Exposed" number="26">The exposed foam board insulation in the crawl space represents a fire hazard. Although this is a common occurrence, it is recommended that this insulation be removed or covered for improved safety.</item>
        <item name="TREC Limitations I-A" number="27">TREC LIMITATIONS: The inspector is not required to inspect flatwork or detention/ retention pond (expect as related to slope and drainage); determine area hydrology or the presence or underground water; or determine the efficiency or operation of underground or surface drainage systems.</item>
    </infobutton>
</infobuttons>